[交响乐调音]
[ORCHESTRA TUNING]
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
大卫·马兰：好的
DAVID MALAN: All right.
这是CS50的Python编程入门
This is CS50's Introduction to Programming with Python.
我的名字是David Malan 这是我们关于正则表达式的一周
My name is David Malan, and this is our week on regular expressions.
因此 正则表达式 也称为正则表达式 实际上只是一种模式
So a regular expression, otherwise known as a regex, is really just a pattern.
实际上 在编程中
And indeed, it's quite common in programming
想要使用模式来匹配某种数据 通常是用户输入
to want to use patterns to match on some kind of data, often user input.
例如 如果用户输入一个电子邮件地址 无论是您的程序
For instance, if the user types in an email address, whether to your program,
或者网站 或者手机上的应用程序
or a website, or an app on your phone, you
理想情况下 可能希望能够验证
might ideally want to be able to validate
他们确实输入了一个电子邮件地址
that they did indeed type in an email address
而不是完全不同的东西
and not something completely different.
所以使用正则表达式 我们将拥有新发现的能力
So using regular expressions, we're going to have the newfound capability
在我们的代码中定义模式 将它们与我们正在使用的数据进行比较
to define patterns in our code to compare them against data that we're
从别人那里接收信息 无论是为了验证它
receiving from someone else, whether it's just to validate it,
或者 即使我们想清理大量的数据
or, heck, even if we want to clean up a whole lot of data
它本身可能是混乱的 因为它也来自我们人类
that itself might be messy because it, too, came from us humans.
在此之前 我们使用这些正则表达式
Before, though, we use these regular expressions,
我建议我们用一些简单的语法来解决一些问题
let me propose that we solve a few problems using just some simpler syntax
看看我们遇到了什么样的限制
and see what kind of limitations we run up against.
我建议在这里打开VS Code
Let me propose that I open up VS Code here,
让我创建一个名为validate.py的文件
and let me create a file called validate.py, the goal at hand
验证用户的电子邮件地址
being to validate, how about just that, a user's email address.
他们来到你的应用程序 他们来到你的网站
They've come to your app, they've come to your website,
他们输入他们的电子邮件地址
they type in their email address, and we want
回答是或否 此电子邮件地址看起来有效
to say yes or no, this email address looks valid.
好吧
All right.
让我继续输入代码validate.py来创建一个新的标签
Let me go ahead and type code of validate.py to create a new tab here.
然后在这个选项卡中 让我继续并开始编写一些代码
And then within this tab, let me go ahead and start writing some code,
怎么样 这让事情简单的开始
how about, that keeps things simple initially.
首先 让我继续并提示用户输入他们的电子邮件地址
First, let me go ahead and prompt the user for their email address.
我将把输入的返回值存储在一个名为email的变量中
And I'll store the return value of input in a variable called email,
问他们“你的邮箱是什么？“
asking them "what's your email?"
问号
question mark.
我将继续至少先发制人地
I'm going to go ahead and preemptively at least
通过最小限度地只调用strie来清理用户的输入
clean up the user's input a little bit by minimally just calling strip
在我对输入的调用结束时 因为回想
at the end of my call to input, because recall
该输入返回一个或多个字符串
that input returns a string or a str.
STR带有一些内置的方法或函数 其中之一
strs come with some built-in methods or functions, one of which
是条状的 具有剥离的效果
is strip, which has the effect of stripping off
左边的任何前导空白或右边的任何尾随空白
any leading whitespace to the left or any trailing whitespace to the right.
所以这一切都会继续下去 至少
So that's just going to go ahead and at least
避免人不小心输入了空格字符
avoid the human having accidentally typed in a space character.
我们要把它扔掉以防万一
We're going to throw it away just in case.
现在我要做一些简单的事情
Now I'm going to do something simple.
对于用户的输入是电子邮件地址
For a user's input to be an email address,
我想我们都同意 它有一个最低限度的
I think we can all agree that it's got a minimal we
在里面的某个地方放一个“符号”
have an @ sign somewhere in it.
所以 让我们从简单的开始
So let's start simple.
如果用户输入了带有@符号的内容 让我们
If the user has typed in something with an @ sign, let's
非常慷慨地说 好的 有效的 看起来像一个电子邮件地址
very generously just say, OK, valid, looks like an email address.
如果我们遗漏了@符号 我们就说它无效 因为它显然是
And if we're missing that @ sign, let's say invalid, because clearly it's
不是电子邮件地址
not an email address.
这还不是我的代码的最好版本 但我们将从简单开始
It's not going to be the best version of my code yet, but we'll start simple.
所以我要问这个问题 如果用户的
So I'm going to ask the question, if there is an @ symbol in the user's
电子邮件地址 继续并打印出来 例如 引号 不引号 “有效”
email address, go ahead and print out, for instance, quote, unquote, "valid."
否则 如果没有 我现在很有信心
Else, if there's not, now I'm pretty confident that the email
事实上 地址是无效的
address is, in fact, invalid.
现在 这段代码在做什么？
Now, what is this code doing?
好吧 如果@Sign in Email是一种毕德式的方式 问这个字符串引号
Well, if @ sign in email is a Pythonic way of asking is this string quote,
在这封不带引号的电子邮件中 无论它在哪里--
unquote "@" in this other string email, no matter where it is--
在开头、中间或结尾
at the beginning, the middle, or the end.
它将自动搜索整个字符串为您
It's going to automatically search through the entire string for you
自动的
automatically.
我可以更详细地做这件事
I could do this more verbosely.
我可以使用For循环或While循环
And I could use a for loop or a while loop
并查看用户电子邮件地址中的每个字符
and look at every character in the user's email address,
想看看这是不是@手势
looking to see if it's an @ sign.
但这是Python的优点之一
But this is one of the things that's nice about Python.
你可以用更少的钱做更多的事情
You can do more with less.
所以只要说如果“@”在电子邮件中引用 不引用
So just by saying if "@" quote, unquote in email,
我们正在实现同样的结果 我们要找回真我
we're achieving that same result. We're going to get back true
如果它在那里的某个地方 那么它是有效的 否则就是假的
if it's somewhere in there, thus valid, or false if it is not.
现在 让我继续在我的终端窗口中运行这个程序
Well, let me go ahead now and run this program in my terminal window
使用valiate.py的python
with python of validate.py.
接下来 我会给它提供我的电子邮件地址--Malan@Gaveard.edu
And I'm going to go ahead and give it my email address-- malan@harvard.edu,
进来吧
Enter.
事实上 它是有效的
And indeed, it's valid.
看起来是有效的 是有效的
Looks valid, is valid.
但当然 从技术上讲 这个计划是失败的
But of course, this program is technically broken.
这是一辆破车
It's buggy.
如果有人输入 会是什么示例输入
What would be an example input, if someone
可能想在这里自愿回答 这将被认为是有效的
might like to volunteer an answer here, that would be considered valid
但你我都知道这真的是无效的？
but you and I know it really isn't valid?
观众：是的 谢谢
AUDIENCE: Yeah, thank you.
举个例子 你只需要输入两个符号就行了
Well, for instance, you can type just two signs and that's it,
而且它仍然有效--
and it'll still be valid--
根据你的程序仍然有效 但遗漏了一些东西
still be valid according to your program, but missing something.
大卫·马兰：没错
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
我们在这里设定了一个很低的标准
We've set a very low bar here.
事实上 如果我继续并重新运行valiate.py的python
In fact, if I go ahead and rerun python of validate.py,
我只需输入一个@符号 就这样--没有用户名 没有域名
and I'll just type in one @ sign, that's it-- no username, no domain name,
这看起来不像是电子邮件地址
this doesn't really look like an email address.
但不幸的是 我的代码认为它实际上是 因为它显然是
But unfortunately, my code thinks it, in fact, is, because it's obviously
我只是在寻找一个单独的“标志”
just looking for an @ sign alone.
那么 我们如何才能改进这一点呢？
Well, how could we improve this?
嗯 至少一个电子邮件地址 我想 往往会有
Well, minimally an email address, I think, tends to have,
虽然这实际上不是一个要求
though this is not actually a requirement,
倾向于至少有一个@符号和一个点 可能在域中的某个地方
tends to have an @ sign and a single dot at least, maybe somewhere in the domain
姓名--So Malan@atherard.edu
name-- so malan@harvard.edu.
那么让我们也来检查一下那个点
So let's check for that dot as well.
但再说一次 严格来说 情况甚至不一定是这样的
But again, strictly speaking it doesn't even have to be that case.
但我会选择我自己的电子邮件地址 至少目前是这样 作为我们的测试案例
But I'm going for my own email address, at least for now, as our test case.
所以让我继续更改我的代码 并说 不仅@在电子邮件中
So let me go ahead and change my code now and say, not only if @ is in email,
但Dot也在电子邮件中
but also dot is in email as well.
所以我现在问你两个问题
So I'm asking now two questions.
我有两个布尔表达式--If@in Email
I have two Boolean expressions-- if @ in email,
我把它们逻辑地进行AND运算--可以说 这是一个逻辑AND运算
and I'm anding them together logically-- this is a logical and, so to speak.
因此 如果@在电子邮件中 Dot在电子邮件中
So if it's the case that @ is in email and dot is in email, OK,
现在我要继续说有效
now I'm going to go ahead and say valid.
好的
All right.
这似乎仍然适用于我的电子邮件地址
This would still seem to work for my email address.
让我继续运行pythonvaliate.py Malan@atherard.edu 回车
Let me go ahead and run python validate.py, malan@harvard.edu, Enter,
当然 这是合理的 这是预料之中的
and that, of course, is valid is expected.
但在这里 我们也可以有点敌意 输入一些东西
But here, too, we can be a little adversarial and type in something
像“@”这样的无稽之谈
nonsensical like "@."
不幸的是 这也会被误认为是正确的
and unfortunately, that, too, is going to be mistaken as valid,
即使仍然没有用户名、域名或类似的东西
even though there's still no username, domain name, or anything like that.
所以我认为我们在这方面需要更有条理一些
So I think we need to be a little more methodical here.
事实上 请注意 如果我这样做 @符号可以在任何地方
In fact, notice that if I do this like this, the @ sign can be anywhere,
圆点可以在任何地方
and the dot can be anywhere.
但是如果我假设用户将拥有一个传统域名
But if I'm assuming the user is going to have a traditional domain
收割网或gmail.com之类的名字 我真的
name like harvard.edu or gmail.com, I really
只想在域名中寻找圆点 不一定
want to look for the dot in the domain name only, not necessarily
只有用户名
just the username.
所以让我继续做这件事
So let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续在这里介绍一些更多的逻辑 而不是这样做
Let me go ahead and introduce a bit more logic here, and instead do this.
让我继续发送电子邮件 分开引用 不引用@sign
Let me go ahead and do email.split of quote, unquote @ sign.
因此 电子邮件同样是一个字符串或字符串
So email, again, is a string or a str.
STR有各种方法 不仅是脱衣 还包括
strs come with methods, not just strip but also
另一种叫Split 顾名思义
another one called split that, as the name implies,
如果指定一个或多个字符 则会将一个字符串拆分为多个字符
will split one str into multiple ones if you give it a character or more
在上面分开
to split on.
希望这封邮件能从传统电子邮件中返回给我两个部分
So this is hopefully going to return to me two parts from a traditional email
地址、用户名和域名
address, the username and the domain name.
事实证明 我可以解开这一系列的回答
And it turns out I can unpack that sequence of responses
通过这样做--用户名逗号域等于这个
by doing this-- username comma domain equals this.
我可以将其存储在列表或其他结构中
I could store it in a list or some other structure,
但如果我事先已经知道我期待什么样的价值
but if I already know in advance what kinds of values I'm expecting,
一个用户名和一个域名 我要
a username and hopefully a domain, I'm going
要继续这样做 只需同时定义两个变量
to go ahead and do it like this instead and just define two variables at once
在一行代码上
on one line of code.
现在我要说得更准确一点
And now I'm going to be a little more precise.
如果用户名--如果用户名 那么我将继续
If username-- if username, then I'm going to go ahead
说 打印“有效”
and say, print "valid."
否则 我将继续说打印“无效”
Else, I'm going to go ahead and say print "invalid."
现在 这还不够好
Now, this isn't good enough.
但我现在至少在检查用户名是否存在
But I'm at least checking for the presence of a username now.
你可能以前没见过 但如果你简单地
And you might not have seen this before, but if you simply
问一个类似“如果用户名是字符串”这样的问题
ask a question like "if username," and username is a string,
好的 用户名--“如果用户名”能给我
well, username-- "if username" is going to give me
如果用户名不是NONE或QUOTE 则回答正确
a true answer if username is anything except none or quote,
不引用“什么都没有 ”
unquote "nothing."
因此这里有一个真实的值 即如果用户名至少有一个字符
So there's a truthy value here, whereby if username has at least one character,
这将被认为是真的
that's going to be considered true.
但如果用户名没有字符 它将
But if username has no characters, it's going
有效地被认为是错误的价值
to be considered a false value effectively.
但这还不够好
But this isn't good enough.
我不想只检查用户名
I don't want to just check for username.
我还想检查一下 点是否也在域名中
I want to also check that it's the case that dot is in the domain name as well.
请注意 这里有一点潜在的混乱
So notice here there's a bit of potential confusion
会说英语
with the English language.
在这里 我似乎是在说“如果用户名和点
Here, I seem to be saying "if username and dot
在域中 “就像我在问问题” 如果用户名和点
in domain," as though I'm asking the question, "if the username and the dot
但这并不是这个意思
are in the domain," but that's not what this means.
这是两个不同的布尔表达式--“如果用户名 ”
These are two separate Boolean expressions-- "if username,"
和单独的 “如果点在领域 ”
and separately, "if dot in domain."
如果我把这个放在括号里 我们可以通过把
And if I parenthesis this, we could make that even more clear by putting
圆括号在那里 圆括号在这里
parentheses there, parentheses here.
为了清楚起见 它实际上是两个布尔表达式
So just to be clear, it's really two Boolean expressions
我们是在一起做AND 而不是一个更长的英语句子
that we're anding together, not one longer English-like sentence.
现在 如果我继续运行这个 python valiate.py回车
Now, if I go ahead and run this, python validate.py Enter,
我会再做一次我自己的电子邮件地址 Malan@atherard.edu 这是有效的
I'll do my own email address again, malan@harvard.edu, and that's valid.
看起来我可以忍受这样的事情
And it looks like I could tolerate something like this.
如果我做马兰 就说 哈佛 我认为目前
If I do malan@, just say, harvard, I think at the moment
这将是无效的
this is going to be invalid.
现在 也许顶级域名哈佛存在
Now, maybe the top-level domain harvard exists.
但目前 我们似乎在寻找更多的东西
But at the moment, it looks like we're looking for something more.
我们也在寻找顶级域名 比如.edu
We're looking for a top-level domain too, like .edu.
目前 我们只认为这是无效的
For now, we'll just consider this to be invalid.
但这不仅仅是我们想要做的--
But it's not just that we want to do--
这不仅仅是因为我们想要检查用户名是否存在
it's not just that we want to check for the presence of a username
和一个圆点的存在
and the presence of a dot.
让我们说得更具体些
Let's be more specific.
让我们现在开始缩小这个项目的范围
Let's start to now narrow the scope of this program,
不仅仅是关于一般的电子邮件 还有关于EDU地址
not just to be about generic emails more generally, but about edu addresses,
例如 对于美国大学里的一些人来说
so specifically for someone in a US university, for instance,
其电子邮件地址往往以.edu结尾
whose email address tends to end with .edu.
我可以说得更准确一点
I can be a little more precise.
你可能已经回想起这个函数了
And you might recall this function already.
而不是简单地说 在域中的某个地方有一个点
Instead of just saying, is there a dot somewhere in domain,
让我说 域名以引号结尾 非引号“.edu”
let me instead say, and the domain ends with quote, unquote ".edu."
现在我们更加精确了
Now we're being even more precise.
我们希望至少有一个不为空的用户名--不仅仅是引号
We want there to be minimally a username that's not empty-- it's not just quote,
不引用“Nothing”--我们希望域名实际上以.edu结尾
unquote "nothing"-- and we want the domain name to actually end with .edu.
让我继续运行valiate.py的python
Let me go ahead and run python of validate.py.
为了确保我没有把事情搞得更糟
And just to make sure I haven't made things even worse,
至少让我测试一下我自己的电子邮件地址 它看起来确实有效
let me at least test my own email address, which does seem to be valid.
现在 我似乎至少需要提供一个用户名
Now, it seems that I minimally need to provide a username,
因为我们确实有这张支票
because we definitely do have that check in place.
所以我要继续说 马兰
So I'm going to go ahead and say malan.
现在我要继续说“
And now I'm going to go ahead and say @.
而且看起来我可能有点恶毒
And it looks like I could be a little malicious here,
只需说Malan@.edu 就像是最小限度的会面
just say malan@.edu, as though minimally meeting
此模式的要求
the requirements of this pattern.
当然 这被认为是有效的
And that, of course, is considered valid,
但我非常肯定 在Malan@.edu上没有人
but I'm pretty sure there's no one at malan@.edu.
我们需要在那里有一些域名
We need to have some domain name in there.
因此 我们仍然没有那么慷慨
So we're still not being quite as generous.
现在 我们完全可以继续迭代这个程序
Now, we could absolutely continue to iterate on this program,
我们可以添加更多的布尔表达式
and we could add some more Boolean expressions.
我们也许可以使用一些其他的Python方法
We could maybe use some other Python methods
为了更精确地检查点的左边是否有东西
for checking more precisely is there something to the left of the dot,
点的右边
to the right of the dot.
我们可以多次使用split
We could use split multiple times.
但老实说 这只是迅速升级
But honestly, this just escalates quickly.
就像 你最终不得不写很多代码
Like, you end up having to write a lot of code just
来表达一些相对简单的东西--
to express something that's relatively simple in spirit--
就像电子邮件地址一样格式化它
just format this like an email address.
那么 我们如何才能改善这一点呢？
So how can we go about improving this?
Python中有一个正则表达式库
Well, it turns out in Python there's a library for regular expressions.
它被称为简洁的R-E 在图书馆里
It's called succinctly R-E. And in the re library,
你有很多能力来定义和检查 甚至取代
you have a lot of capabilities to define and check for and even replace
模式.
patterns.
同样 正则表达式也是一种模式
Again, a regular expression is a pattern.
这个库 Python中的re库
And this library, the re library in Python,
会让我们定义其中的一些模式
is going to let us define some of these patterns,
比如电子邮件地址的模式 然后
like a pattern for an email address, and then
使用一些内置函数来验证
use some built-in functions to actually validate
用户的输入与该模式相对应
a user's input against that pattern or even
使用这些模式来更改用户的输入
use these patterns to change the user's input
或者从中提取部分信息
or extract partial information therefrom.
我们将看到所有这些和更多的例子
We'll see examples of all this and more.
那么 我可以和应该如何使用这个图书馆呢？
So what can and should I do with this library?
首先 它有很多功能
Well, first and foremost, it comes with a lot of functionality.
例如 这里是官方文档的URL
Here is the URL, for instance, to the official documentation.
我建议我们集中精力
And let me propose that we focus on using
图书馆里最通用的功能之一 就是这个--搜索
one of the most versatile functions in the library, namely this-- search.
re.search是函数的名称 re模块
re.search is the name of the function and the re module
它允许你传入一些参数
that allows you to pass in a few arguments.
第一个是你想要搜索的模式
The first is going to be a pattern that you want to search for in,
例如 来自用户的字符串
for instance, a string that came from a user.
这里的字符串参数将是实际的字符串
The string argument here is going to be the actual string that you
我想寻找这种模式
want to search for that pattern.
还有第三个参数可选
And then there's a third argument optionally
那可是一大堆旗子
that's a whole bunch of flags.
一般来说 标志就像是可以传入的参数
A flag in general is like a parameter you can pass in
修改函数的行为
to modify the behavior of the function.
但一开始 我们甚至不打算用这个
But initially, we're not even going to use this.
我们只需要传递几个参数
We're just going to pass in a couple of arguments instead.
所以让我继续使用这个Re库 这个正则表达式
So let me go ahead and employ this re library, this regular expression
库 并在此设计基础上逐步改进
library, and just improve on this design incrementally.
所以我们不会一下子解决这个问题
So we're not going to solve this problem all at once,
但我们将采取一些渐进的步骤
but we'll take some incremental steps.
我将回到这里的VS代码
I'm going to go back to VS Code here.
现在我要继续下去 去掉大部分代码
And I'm going to go ahead now and get rid of most of this code.
但我要进入我的文件顶部 在秋季的第一天
But I'm going to go into the top of my file and first of fall,
导入此Re库
import this re library.
因此 导入环使我可以访问该功能以及更多功能
So import re gives me access to that function and more.
现在 在我以与以前相同的方式获得用户输入之后
Now, after I've gotten the user's input in the same way as before,
去掉任何前导或尾随空格
stripping off any leading or trailing whitespace,
现在 我只是简单地使用这个函数
I'm just going to use this function super trivially for now,
尽管这并不是真正向前迈出的一大步
even though this isn't really a big step forward.
我要说的是 如果re.earch包含引号 请取消引号“@”
I'm going to say, if re.search contains quote, unquote "@"
在电子邮件地址中 然后让我们继续打印“有效”
in the email address, then let's go ahead and print "valid."
否则 让我们继续打印“无效”
Else, let's go ahead and print "invalid."
目前 这真的不比我的第一个版本好多少
At the moment, this is really no better than my very first version
我刚才问的是 如果@在电子邮件地址签名的话
where I was just asking Python, if @ sign in the email address.
但现在我至少开始通过使用自己的re.earch来使用这个库了
But now I'm at least beginning to use this library by using its own re.search
函数 目前您可以假定该函数有效地返回真值
function, which for now you can assume returns a true value effectively
如果@符号确实是一封电子邮件的话
if, indeed, the @ sign is an email.
为了确保这个版本能像我预期的那样工作 让我继续
Just to make sure that this version does work as I expect, let me go ahead
然后运行validate.py的python并回车
and run python of validate.py and Enter.
我会输入我的实际电子邮件地址 然后我们就可以继续营业了
I'll type in my actual email address, and we're back in business.
但当然 这并不是很好 因为如果我同样
But of course, this is not great, because if I similarly
运行这个版本的程序 只需输入@符号
run this version of the program and just type in an @ sign,
不是电子邮件地址 但我的代码当然认为它是有效的
not an email address, and yet my code, of course, thinks it is valid.
那么 我怎么才能做得比这更好呢？
So how can I do better than this?
在正则表达式领域 我们需要更多的词汇
Well, we need a bit more vocabulary in the realm of regular expressions,
为了能够更准确地表达我们自己
in order to be able to express ourselves a little more precisely.
真的 我想最终定义的模式
Really, the pattern I want to ultimately define
我希望左边有个东西
is going to be something like, I want there to be something to the left,
然后是一个@符号 然后是右边的东西
then an @ sign, then something to the right.
右边的东西应该以.edu结尾 但也应该有
And that something to the right should end with .edu but should also have
在.edu之前 比如哈佛 耶鲁
something before the .edu, like Harvard, or Yale,
美国的其他学校也是如此
or any other school in the US as well.
我该怎么做呢？
Well, how can I go about doing this?
事实证明 在正则表达式的世界中 无论是在Python中
Well, it turns out that in the world of regular expressions, whether in Python
或者其他语言中 有一些特定的符号
or a lot of other languages as well, there are certain symbols
可以用来定义模式
that you can use to define patterns.
目前 我只使用了字面上的原始文本
At the moment, I've just used literal raw text.
如果我回到我的代码这里 这在技术上
If I go back to my code here, this technically
正则表达式是一个正则表达式
qualifies as a regular expression.
我传入了一个带引号的字符串 里面有一个@符号
I've passed in a quoted string inside of which is an @ sign.
现在 这不是一个非常有趣的模式
Now, that's not a very interesting pattern.
只是一个@符号
It's just an @ sign.
但事实证明 一旦你有机会访问正则表达式
But it turns out that once you have access to regular expressions
或者提供该功能的库 您可以
or a library that offers that feature, you can more
你可以像下面这样有力地表达自己
powerfully express yourself as follows.
让我来揭示一下 你传递给re.search的模式
Let me reveal that the pattern that you pass to re.search
可以用一大堆特殊的符号
can take a whole bunch of special symbols.
这只是其中的一部分
And here's just some of them.
在我们将要看到的例子中 在我们将要定义的模式中
In the examples we're about to see, in the patterns we're about to define,
这是特殊符号
here are the special symbols.
你可以用一个句号 一个点
You can use a single period, a dot, to just represent
除了换行符和空行以外的任何字符
any character except a newline, a blank line.
也就是说 如果我不在乎字母表中的哪个字母
So that is to say, if I don't really care what letters of the alphabet
在用户的用户名中 我只希望有
are in the user's username, I just want there
是用户名中的一个或多个字符
to be one or more characters in the user's name,
dot可以让我用z 和来表示A
dot allows me to express A through z, uppercase and lowercase,
还有其他一些字母
and a bunch of other letters as well.
* 表示--一个星号--零次或多次重复
* is going to mean-- a single asterisk-- zero or more repetitions.
所以如果我说了什么 那就意味着
So if I say something *, that means that I'm
愿意接受零重复 即
willing to accept either zero repetitions, that is,
什么都没有 或者更多的重复
nothing at all, or more repetitions--
1或2或3或300
1, or 2, or 3, or 300.
如果你在我的模式中看到一个加号
If you see a plus in my pattern, so that's
这意味着一次或多次重复
going to mean one or more repetitions.
也就是说 至少要有一个字符 一个符号
That is to say, there's got to be at least one character there, one symbol,
然后 在那之后还有更多的可选的
and then there's optionally more after that.
然后你可以说零或一次重复
And then you can say zero or one repetition.
您可以在符号后使用单个问号 这将表示
You can use a single question mark after a symbol, and that will say,
我不想要这个角色或一个角色 但这就是我所期望的
I want zero of this character or one, but that's all I'll expect.
最后 会有一种方法
And then lastly, there's going to be a way
要指定特定数量的符号 请执行以下操作
to specify a specific number of symbols.
如果你使用这些花括号和一个数字
If you use these curly braces and a number,
在这里符号表示为m 您可以
represented here symbolically as m, you can
指定需要m次重复 可以是1次、2次、3次或300次
specify that you want m repetitions, be it 1, or 2, or 3, or 300.
您可以自己指定重复次数
You can specify the number of repetitions yourself.
如果你想要一系列的重复 就像你
And if you want a range of repetitions, like you
想要这几个字或者这么多字
want this few characters or this many characters,
您可以在里面使用花括号和两个数字
you can use curly braces and two numbers inside,
在这里称为m和n 这将是m到n个重复的范围
called here m and n, which would be a range of m through n repetitions.
那么 这一切意味着什么呢？
Now, what does all of this mean?
好吧 让我回到VS代码这里 让我们
Well, let me go back to VS Code here, and let
我建议我们进一步迭代这个解决方案
me propose that we iterate on this solution further.
仅仅检查@符号是不够的
It's not sufficient to just check for the @ sign.
我们已经知道了这一点
We know that already.
我们最低限度地想要一些东西放在左边和右边
We minimally want something to the left and to the right.
那么 我该如何代表这一点呢？
So how can I represent that?
我并不真正关心用户的用户名是什么
I don't really care what the user's username is,
或者是字母表中的什么字母 无论是马兰还是其他任何人的
or what letters of the alphabet are in it, be it malan or anyone else's.
所以我要做的是在等号的左边
So what I'm going to do to the left of this equal sign
我将用一个句号--
is I'm going to use a single period--
同样表示除换行符以外的任何字符的圆点
the dot that, again, indicates any character except for a newline.
但我不只想要一个角色
But I don't just want a single character.
否则 该人的用户名只能是某某
Otherwise, the person's username could only a at such and such,
或者b某某
or b at such and such.
我希望是多个这样的角色
I want it to be multiple such characters.
所以我将首先使用*
So I'm going to initially use a *.
所以点*的意思是给我一些左边的东西 我要做另一个
So dot * means give me something to the left, and I'm going to do another one,
点*右边的东西
dot * something to the right.
现在 这并不完美 但至少是向前迈进了一步
Now, this isn't perfect, but it's at least a step forward.
因为现在我要做的就是这样
Because now what I'm going to go ahead and do is this.
我将重新运行valiate.py的python
I'm going to rerun python of validate.py.
我将继续测试我自己的电子邮件地址 只是为了
And I'm going to keep testing my own email address just to make
当然 我没有让事情变得更糟
sure I haven't made things worse.
现在一切都好了
And that's now OK.
现在我要继续输入一些其他的内容
I'm now going to go ahead and type in some other input,
就像没有域名的马兰@怎么样
like how about just malan@ with no domain name whatsoever.
你可能会认为这将是无效的
And you would think this is going to be invalid.
但是 但是 但是它仍然被认为是有效的
But, but, but it's still considered valid.
但为什么会这样呢？
But why is that?
如果我回到这张图表 为什么现在没有域名的情况下会考虑Malan@
If I go back to this chart, why is malan@ with no domain now considered
有效吗？
valid?
我在这里使用.*@.*作为正则表达式 这有什么错误
What's my mistake here by having used .*@.* as my regular expression
还是正则表达式？
or regex?
观众：因为你用的是* 而不是加号
AUDIENCE: Because you're using the * instead of the plus sign.
大卫·马兰：没错
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
再说一次 *表示零次或多次重复
The *, again, means zero or more repetitions.
所以re.earch非常乐意在@符号之后什么都不接受
So re.search is perfectly happy to accept nothing after the @ sign,
因为这将是零重复
because that would be zero repetitions.
所以我认为我至少需要改进这一点 然后回到我这里的代码
So I think I minimally need to evolve this and go back to my code here.
让我继续 把这个从点*改为点+
And let me go ahead and change this from dot * to dot +.
让我把结尾从点*改成点+
And let me change the ending from dot * to dot +
所以现在当我在这里运行代码时--
so that now when I run my code here--
让我继续运行valiate.py的python
let me go ahead and run python of validate.py.
我要像往常一样测试我的电子邮件地址
I'm going to test my email address as always.
还在工作
Still working.
现在让我继续输入之前的相同内容
Now let me go ahead and type in that same thing from before that
意外地被认为是有效的
was accidentally considered valid.
现在我按了回车 最后它是无效的
Now I hit Enter, finally it's invalid.
所以现在我们正在取得一些进展 在多一点
So now we're making some progress on being a little more
准确地知道我们在做什么
precise as to what it is we're doing.
现在 我要在这里指出 就像编程中的几乎所有事情一样
Now, I'll note here, like with almost everything in programming,
包括Python在内 通常有多种方法来解决相同的问题
Python included, there's often multiple ways to solve the same problem.
有没有人在我的代码中发现了什么
And does anyone see a way in my code here
如果我忘记了加号运算符的存在 我可以稍作调整
that I can make a slight tweak if I forgot that the plus operator exists
然后重新使用*？
and go back to using a *?
如果我只允许你使用圆点和星号
If I allowed you only to use dots and only stars,
你能再创造一个加号的概念吗？
could you recreate the notion of plus?
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yes.
使用另一个点 点点*
Use another dot, dot dot *.
大卫·马兰：是的
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
因为如果圆点表示任何字符 我们将只使用圆点
Because if a dot means any character, we'll just use a dot.
然后当你想说“or more”时 用另一个点 然后用*
And then when you want to say "or more," use another dot and then the *.
所以等同于点+的应该是点*
So equivalent to dot + would have been dot dot *,
因为第一个点表示任何字符 而第二对点表示任何字符
because the first dot means any character, and the second pair
在字符中 点*表示零个或多个其他字符
of characters, dot *, means zero or more other characters.
需要明确的是 它不一定是同一个角色
And to be clear, it doesn't have to be the same character.
只做点或点*并不意味着您的整个用户名需要
Just by doing dot or dot * does not mean your whole username needs to be
A 或AA 或AAA 或AAAA
a, or aa, or aaa, or aaaa.
它可以随每个符号而不同
It can vary with each symbol.
它只是指背靠背的任何字符的零个或多个
It just means zero or more of any character back to back.
所以我可以在左边和右边做这件事
So I could do this on both the left and the right.
哪一个更好？
Which one is better?
你知道 这要看情况
You know, it depends.
我认为可以提出一个论点 这一点甚至更清楚 因为它
I think an argument could be made that this is even more clear, because it's
很明显 现在有一个圆点 意思是任何字符
obvious now that there's a dot, which means any character,
然后是圆点*
and then there's the dot *.
但如果你习惯于经常这样做
But if you're in the habit of doing this frequently,
像加号这样的东西存在的原因之一
one of the reasons things like the plus exist
只是将您的代码合并到更简洁的内容中
is just to consolidate your code into something a little more succinct.
如果你对现在看到的好处很熟悉
And if you're familiar with seeing the plus now,
也许这对你来说更具可读性
maybe this is more readable to you.
所以再一次 就像更一般的Python一样
So again, just like with Python more generally,
你会经常看到不同的方式来表达相同的模式
you're going to often see different ways to express the same patterns,
理性的人可能会同意 也可能不同意
and reasonable people might agree or disagree
哪种方式比另一种方式更好
as to which way is better than another.
好吧 让我向你提议 我们可以认为
Well, let me propose to you that we can think
关于这两个模型的更多一点图形化
about both of these models a little more graphically.
如果你觉得这有点神秘 让我继续说下去
If this looks a little cryptic to you, let me go ahead
并回溯到此正则表达式的前一个实例 该正则表达式
and rewind to the previous incarnation of this regular expression, which
只有一个点*
was just a single dot *.
这个正则表达式.*@.*又意味着什么？
This regular expression, .*@.* means what again?
它表示零个或多个字符 后跟文字符号@
It means zero or more characters followed by a literal @ sign followed
零个或多个其他字符
by zero or more other characters.
现在 当您将此模式作为参数传递给re.earch时
Now when you pass this pattern in as an argument to re.search,
它将从左到右读取它 然后使用
it's going to read it from left to right and then use
它尝试与输入进行匹配 在本例中为电子邮件
it to try to match against the input, email, in this case,
用户输入的
that the user typed in.
现在 你的电脑怎么样了 re.earch怎么样了
Now, how is the computer, how is re.search
要跟踪用户的电子邮件是否与此模式匹配？
going to keep track of whether or not the user's email matches this pattern?
嗯 结果是它将使用一种实现的机器
Well, it turns out that it's going to be using a machine of sorts implemented
在被称为有限状态机或更多的软件中
in software known as a finite state machine, or more
形式上 一个不确定的有限自动机
formally, a nondeterministic finite automaton.
如果我们用图形来描述它 它的工作方式如下所示
And the way it works, if we depict this graphically, is as follows.
Re.earch函数从这里开始 处于所谓的开始状态
The re.search function starts over here in a so-called start state.
这就是它开始时的那种情况
That's the sort of condition in which it begins.
然后它将从左到右读取用户的电子邮件地址
And then it's going to read the user's email address from left to right.
它将决定是否留在第一个状态
And it's going to decide whether or not to stay in this first state
或者转换到下一个状态
or transition to the next state.
例如 在第一个状态中 当用户正在阅读我的电子邮件地址时
So for instance, in this first state, as the user is reading my email address,
它将沿着这个弯曲的边缘向上和向四周移动
malan@harvard.edu, it's going to follow this curved edge up and around
对它本身来说 是一种反身性的优势
to itself, a reflexive edge.
它被标记为点 因为点 再一次 只是指任何字符
And it's labeled dot, because dot, again, just means any character.
因此 由于该函数正在读取我的电子邮件地址 即Malan@atherard.edu
So as the function is reading my email address, malan@harvard.edu,
从左到右 它将遵循如下的转变
from left to right, it's going to follow these transitions as follows,
并购-并购-L-A-N
M-A-L-A-N.
然后 它有望在这种过渡之后
And then it's hopefully going to follow this transition
转到第二个状态 因为这台机器中有一个字面符号@
to the second state, because there's a literal @ sign both in this machine
以及在我的电子邮件地址中
as well as in my email address.
然后它将尝试读取我地址的其余部分 H-A-R-V-A-R-D点E-D-U
Then it's going to try to read the rest of my address, H-A-R-V-A-R-D dot E-D-U,
就是这样
and that's it.
然后电脑就会进行检查
And then the computer is going to check.
它最终是以接受状态 最终状态
Did it end up in an accept state, a final state,
它实际上在这里被生动地描绘出来
that's actually depicted here pictorially
两个圆圈 一个在另一个里面 有一点不同吗？
a little differently with double circles, one inside of the other?
这就意味着 如果计算机发现自己在那一秒
And that just means that if the computer finds itself in that second
在已经读取所有用户输入之后的接受状态
accept state after having read all of the user's input,
这确实是一个有效的电子邮件地址
it is, indeed, a valid email address.
如果碰巧 机器以某种方式结束了
If by some chance, the machine somehow ended up
停留在第一种状态 它没有双圈
stuck in that first state, which does not have double circles
并且因此不是接受状态 则计算机
and is therefore not an accept state, the computer
这是一个无效的电子邮件地址
would conclude this is an invalid email address instead.
相比之下 如果我们回到我的另一个版本
By contrast, if we go back to my other your version
我在代码的左右两边都用了点+
of the code where I instead had dot plus on both the left and the right,
回想一下 re.search将使用其中一个状态机
recall that re.search is going to use one of these state machines
为了从左到右决定是否接受用户的
in order to decide from left to right whether or not to accept the user's
输入 如malan@harvard.edu
input, like malan@harvard.edu.
我们能从开始状态 到接受状态吗
Can we get from the start state, so to speak, to an accept state
来决定 对 这其实是符合规律的
to decide, yep, this was, in fact, meeting the pattern?
好吧 让我们假设这个不确定的有限自动机
Well, let's propose that this nondeterministic finite automaton
看起来像这样
looked like this instead.
我们将从最左边的开始状态开始
We're going to start as before in the leftmost start state,
我们必须在第一条边上使用一个字符
and we're going to necessarily consume one character per this first edge,
它用一个点标记 表示我们可以使用任何一个字符
which is labeled with a dot to indicate that we can consume any one character,
比如malan@harvard.edu中的m
like the m in malan@harvard.edu.
然后我们可以花一些时间在@符号之前消耗更多的字符
Then we can spend some time consuming more characters before the @ sign,
所以A-L-A-N
so the A-L-A-N.
然后我们可以使用@符号
Then we can consume the @ sign.
那么我们至少可以多消耗一个角色 因为回忆一下
Then we can consume at least one more character, because recall
正则表达式这次有点加号
that the regex has dot plus this time.
如果我们愿意的话 我们可以使用更多的字符
And then we can consume even more characters if we want.
所以如果我们首先在harvard.edu中使用H
So if we first consume the H in harvard.edu,
然后留下A-R-V-A-R-D 然后点E-D-U
then leaves the A-R-V-A-R-D, and then dot E-D-U.
现在我们也到了故事的结尾
And now here, too, we're at the end of the story,
但我们处于接受状态 因为最后的圆圈
but we're in an accept state, because that circle at the end
一共有两个圆 这意味着如果计算机 如果这个函数
has two circles total, which means that if the computer, if this function,
在读取了用户的全部
finds itself in that accept state after reading the entirety of the user's
实际上 它也是一个有效的电子邮件地址
input, it is, too, in fact, a valid email address.
如果相反 我们被困在另一个州
If by contrast, we had gotten stuck in one of those other states,
无法跟随一个过渡 其中一个边缘
unable to follow a transition, one of those edges,
并且因此不能在用户的输入中从左到右取得进展
and therefore unable to make progress in the user's input from left to right,
那么我们将不得不得出结论 电子邮件地址实际上是无效的
then we would have to conclude that email address is, in fact, invalid.
那么 我们如何才能进一步批准这个代码呢？
Well, how can we go upon approving this code further?
现在让我提议 我们不仅要检查用户名 还要检查一些
Let me propose now that we check not only for a username and also something
在用户名之后 类似于域名 但最低要求字符串
after the username, like a domain name, but minimally require that the string
也以.edu结尾
ends with .edu as well.
嗯 我想我可以很直接地这样做
Well, I think I could do this fairly straightforward.
我不仅希望在@符号之后有一些东西
Not only do I want there to be something after the @ sign,
就像哈佛这样的域名一样 我希望整件事以.edu结尾
like the domain like Harvard, I want the whole thing to end with .edu.
但这里有一点危险
But there's a little bit of danger here.
现在以这种方式实现我的正则表达式 我做错了什么
What have I done wrong by implementing my regular expression now in this way,
通过使用.+@.+.edu？
by using .+@.+.edu?
这个版本可能会出什么问题？
What could go wrong with this version?
观众：这个圆点--这个圆点意味着什么
AUDIENCE: The dot is-- the dot means something
否则在本文中 它意味着三次或三次以上的重复
else in this context, where it means three or more repetitions
这就是为什么它会解释它[INAUDIBLE]..
of a character, which is why it will interpret it [INAUDIBLE]..
大卫·马兰：没错
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
尽管我的意思是字面意思是.edu 一个句号
Even though I mean for it to mean literally .edu, a period,
然后是.edu 不幸的是 在正则表达式世界中
and then .edu, unfortunately in the world of regular expressions,
点表示任何字符 这意味着从技术上讲 该字符串可以结束
dot means any character, which means that this string could technically end
在埃杜 或贝杜 或雪松 等等 但这并不是 事实上 我想要的
in aedu, or bedu, or cedu, and so forth, but that's not, in fact, that I want.
那么 我现在对如何解决这个问题有什么直觉吗？
So any instincts now as to how I could fix this problem?
让我更清楚地说明这个问题
And let me demonstrate the problem more clearly.
让我继续在这里运行这段代码
Let me go ahead and run this code here.
让我继续输入Malan@greavard.edu
Let me go ahead and type in malan@harvard.edu.
而且一如既往 这确实奏效了
And as always, this does, in fact, work.
但看看这里会发生什么
But watch what happens here.
让我继续做马兰@哈佛 然后--
Let me go ahead and do malan@harvard and then--
马兰@哈佛？埃杜 输入 这也是有效的
malan@harvard?edu, Enter, that, too, is valid.
所以我可以把任何角色放在那里 它仍然会被接受
So I could put any character there and it's still going to be accepted.
但我不想要？埃杜
But I don't want ?edu.
我想要.EDU字面意思
I want .edu literally.
那么 对于我们如何在这里解决这个问题 你有什么直觉吗？
Any instincts, then, for how we can solve this problem here?
我如何才能获得这个新函数re.earch和正则表达式
How can I get this new function, re.search, and a regular expression
更笼统地说 字面意思是一个点 你觉得呢？
more generally, to literally mean a dot, might you think?
观众：你可以用转义字符 反斜杠？
AUDIENCE: You can use the escape character, the backslash?
大卫·马兰：确实如此
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
所谓的逃逸角色 我们以前在外面见过
The so-called escape character, which we've seen before outside
正则表达式的上下文 当我们讨论换行符时
of the context of regular expressions when we talked about newlines.
反斜杠n是一种告诉计算机我需要换行符的方式
Backslash n was a way of telling the computer I want a newline,
但实际上并没有真正地按下Enter键并亲自移动光标
but without actually literally hitting Enter and moving the cursor yourself.
你不会想在屏幕上出现文字n的
And you don't want a literal n on the screen.
因此 反斜杠n是转义n并表示您需要换行符的一种方式
So backslash n was a way to escape n and convey that you want a newline.
事实证明 正则表达式使用类似的技术
It turns out regular expressions use a similar technique
在这里解决这个问题
to solve this problem here.
事实上 让我来看看我的正则表达式
In fact, let me go into my regular expression.
在最后一个点之前 让我加一个反斜杠
And before that final dot, let me put a single backslash.
在正则表达式的世界中 这是一个所谓的特殊序列
In the world of regular expressions, this is a so-called special sequence.
它表明 根据这个反斜杠和一个单点
And it indicates, per this backslash and a single dot,
我真的想要在一个点上匹配
that I literally want to match on a dot.
这并不是说我想要匹配任何角色 然后就是edu
It's not that I want to match on any character and then edu.
我想匹配一个点 或一个句点 edu
I want to match on a dot, or a period, edu.
但是我们不希望Python曲解这个反斜杠
But we don't want Python to misinterpret this backslash
作为转义序列的开始 一些特殊的东西 如反斜杠
as beginning an escape sequence, something special like backslash
N 即使我们作为程序员可能会键入两个字符
n, which even though we as the programmer might type two characters
反斜杠n 它实际上被Python解释为一个换行符
backslash n, it really is interpreted by Python as a single newline.
我们不希望在这里出现任何类似的误解
We don't want any kind of misinterpretation like that here.
因此 对于正则表达式 我们还应该做另一件事
So it turns out there's one other thing we should do for regular expressions
像这样有一个反斜杠是这样用的
like this that have a backslash used in this way.
我想向Python指定我想要这个字符串、这个正则表达式
I want to specify to Python that I want this string, this regular expression
在双引号中 将被视为原始字符串
in double quotes, to be treated as a raw string,
字面意思是将r放在字符串的开头
literally putting an r at the beginning of the string
向Python指示您不应尝试解释
to indicate to Python that you should not try to interpret
以常规方式添加任何反斜杠
any backslashes in the usual way.
我想按字面意思传递反斜杠、点和edu
I want to literally pass the backslash and the dot and the edu
进入这个特殊的功能 搜索 在本例中
into this particular function, search, in this case.
因此它在本质上类似于在格式开头使用f
So it's similar in spirit to using that f at the beginning of a format
字符串 当然 它告诉Python以某种方式格式化字符串
string, which, of course, tells Python to format the string in a certain way,
插入可能在大括号之间的变量
plugging in variables that might be between curly braces.
但在本例中 r表示原始字符串
But in this case, r indicates a raw string
我想要完全按照原样传递
that I want passed in exactly as is.
现在 只有在使用反斜杠的情况下 才有必要这样做
Now, it's only strictly necessary if you are, in fact, using backslashes
表示您需要一些特殊的序列 如反斜杠圆点
to indicate that you want some special sequence, like backslash dot.
但总的来说 这可能是一个好习惯
But in general, it's probably a good habit
了解如何只对所有正则表达式使用原始字符串
to get into to just use raw strings for all of your regular expressions
所以如果你最终回到里面 做一些改变 增加一些东西
so that if you eventually go back in, make a change, make an addition,
您不会意外地引入反斜杠
you don't accidentally introduce a backslash
然后忘记这可能有一些特殊的或被误解的意思
and then forget that that might have some special or misinterpreted meaning.
好了 让我们继续尝试这个新的正则表达式
Well, let me go ahead and try this new regular expression.
我将清除我的终端窗口 运行VALIDATE--
I'll clear my terminal window, run python of validate--
运行valiate.py的python
run python of validate.py.
然后我会正确地输入我的电子邮件地址：Malan@atherard.edu
And then I'll type in my email address correctly, malan@harvard.edu.
幸运的是 这一点仍然有效
And that's, fortunately, still valid.
让我清空屏幕并再次运行一次 即valiate.py的python
Let me clear my screen and run it one more time, python of validate.py.
这一次 让我们把它错误地输入为Malan@Harvard？Edu
And this time, let's mistype it as malan@harvard?edu,
很明显那里没有一个圆点
whereby there's obviously not a dot there,
但上一次还有其他一些单字被曲解了
but there is some other single character that last time was misinterpreted
是有效的
as valid.
但这一次 既然我已经改进了正则表达式
But this time, now that I've improved my regular expression,
它被发现确实是无效的
it's discovered as, indeed, invalid.
现在对@左边的匹配技巧有什么疑问吗？
Any questions now on this technique for matching something to the left of the @
签名 右边的东西 现在明确地以.edu结尾？
sign, something to the right, and now ending with .edu explicitly?
观众：当用户插入多个@符号时会发生什么？
AUDIENCE: What happens when user inserts multiple @ signs?
大卫·马兰：问得好
DAVID MALAN: A good question.
你把我叫到了这里
And you kind of called me out here.
好吧 如果有疑问 让我们试一试
Well, when in doubt, let's try.
让我继续执行validate.py、Malan@atherard.edu、
Let me go ahead and do python of validate.py, malan@@@harvard.edu,
这也是不正确的 不幸的是 我的代码认为它是有效的
which also is incorrect, unfortunately, my code thinks it's valid.
因此 这是另一个需要解决的问题 但目前还存在不足
So another problem to solve, but a shortcoming for now.
到目前为止 关于这些正则表达式还有其他问题吗？
Other questions on these regular expressions thus far?
观众：你能用大括号m代替反斜杠吗？
AUDIENCE: Can you use curly brackets m instead of backslash?
大卫·马兰：你能用大括号代替反斜杠吗？
DAVID MALAN: Can you use curly brackets instead of backslash?
在这种情况下不是这样
Not in this case.
如果你想要一个字面点 反斜线点是字面上的方法
If you want a literal dot, backslash dot is the way to do it literally.
关于正则表达式的另一个问题如何？
How about one other question on regular expressions?
观众：这和Google Forms用来订购的东西是一样的吗
AUDIENCE: Is this the same thing that Google Forms uses in order
为了将数据分类 假设是一些--如果您有多个人发送
to categorize data in, let's say, some-- if you've got multiple people sending
关于一些反馈的请求？
in requests about some feedback?
他们是否对他们获得的数据进行分类
Do they categorize the data that they get
使用这个特殊的正则表达式吗？
using this particular regular expression thing?
大卫·马兰：确实如此
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
如果你曾经使用过谷歌表格 而不仅仅是提交它
If you've ever used Google Forms to not just submit it
但要创建Google表单 菜单选项之一
but to create a Google Form, one of the menu options
是为了响应验证 至少在英语中是这样
is for response validation, in English at least.
这样做的目的是指定
And what that allows you to do is specify
用户必须输入电子邮件地址或URL
that the user has to input an email address, or a URL,
或者一根有一定长度的绳子
or a string of some length.
但还有一个更强大的功能 你们中的一些人
But there's an even more powerful feature that some of you
可能从来没有注意到
may not have ever noticed.
事实上 如果你想打开谷歌表格
And indeed, if you'd like to open up Google Forms,
临时创建一个新的表单 然后四处查看 您将真正看到
create a new form temporarily, and poke around, you will actually see,
至少在英语中 引号 不引号“Regular Expression”
in English at least, quote, unquote "regular expression"
提到的一种机制 您可以
mentioned as one of the mechanisms you can
用于验证用户对您的Google表单的输入
use to validate your users' input into your Google Form.
因此 事实上 从今天开始 您可以开始避免特定的下拉列表
So in fact, after today you can start avoiding the specific dropdowns
类似的电子邮件地址或URL等
of like email address, or URL, or the like,
你也可以准确地表达你自己的模式
and you can express your own patterns precisely as well.
正则表达式甚至可以在VS代码本身中使用
Regular expressions can even be used in VS Code itself.
如果您在VS代码中查找或执行查找和替换
If you go and find, or do a find and replace in VS Code,
当然 您可以像您所能做的那样 只需输入单词
you can, of course, just type in words, like you could
到Microsoft Word或Google Docs
into Microsoft Word or Google Docs.
如果选中正确的框 您还可以键入正则表达式
You can also type, if you check the right box, regular expressions
并开始寻找模式 而不是字面上的具体值
and start searching for patterns, not literally specific values.
好吧 让我建议我们现在进一步加强这个实现
Well, let me propose that we now enhance this implementation further
通过引入一些其他的符号 因为现在我的代码
by introducing a few other symbols, because right now with my code,
我一直说我希望我的电子邮件地址以.edu结尾 以.edu开头
I keep saying that I want my email address to end with .edu and start with
一个用户名但我有点太慷慨了
a username, but I'm being a little too generous.
事实上 这对我自己的电子邮件地址来说是正常的
This does, in fact, work as expected for my own email address,
malan@harvard.edu.
但是如果我输入一个句子 比如“我的电子邮件地址
But what if I type in a sentence like, "my email address
是malan@harvard.edu ”假设我已经把它输入到程序中
is malan@harvard.edu," and suppose I've typed that into the program
或者我已经把它输入到谷歌表单里了
or I've typed that into a Google Form?
这将被视为有效或无效？
Is this going to be considered valid or invalid?
好吧 让我们考虑一下
Well, let's consider.
它有@符号 所以我们很好
It's got @ sign, so we're good there.
它在@符号的左边有一个或多个字符
It's got one or more characters to the left of the @ sign.
它在@符号的右边有一个或多个字符
It's got one or more characters to the right of the @ sign.
在@符号的右边有一个文字.edu
It's got a literal .edu somewhere in there to the right of the @ sign.
当然 右边有更多的东西
And granted, there's more stuff to the right.
在我的英语句子的末尾有一个句号
There's literally this period at the end of my English sentence.
但这没关系 因为目前 我的正则表达式不是那么精确
But that's OK, because at the moment, my regular expression is not so precise
也就是说 模式必须以用户名开始 以. edu结束
as to say, the pattern must start with the username and end with the .edu.
从技术上讲 它的左可以说什么更多
Technically, it's left unsaid what more can be to the left
还有什么可以向右
and what more can be to the right.
所以当我按回车键的时候 你会看到整个英文句子
So when I hit Enter now, you'll see that that whole sentence in English
是有效的 这显然不是你想要的
is valid, and that's obviously not what you want.
事实上 考虑使用Google Forms或Office的情况
In fact, consider the case of using Google Forms or Office
365收集用户的数据
365 to collect data from users.
如果不验证输入 用户
If you don't validate your input, your users
可能会输入一个完整的句子或其他东西
might very well type in a full sentence or something else
只是一个印刷错误而不是一封真正的邮件
with a typographical error, not an actual email.
所以如果你只是想复制所有的结果
So if you're just trying to copy all of the results that
已输入到您的表单中 以便您可以粘贴它们
have been typed into your form so you can paste them
Gmail或其他电子邮件程序 它会崩溃
into Gmail or some email program, it's going to break,
因为你会不小心把一整句英语
because you're going to accidentally pay something like a whole English sentence
而不仅仅是一个电子邮件地址
into the program instead of just an email address, which
这是你的邮件期望
is what your mailer expects.
我怎么才能更精确呢？
So how can I be more precise?
好吧 让我提议我们再引入一些符号
Well, let me propose we introduce a few more symbols as well.
在正则表达式的上下文中 这些模式之一
It turns out in the context of a regular expression, one of these patterns,
你可以用这个插入符号 这个小三角形标记
you can use the caret symbol, the little triangular mark,
来表示你想让这个图案
to represent that you want this pattern to match
字符串的开头--不是任何地方
the start of the string specifically-- not anywhere
而是用户字符串的开头
but the start of the user's string.
相比之下 您可以在正则表达式中使用$符号表示您
By contrast, you can use a $ sign in your regular expression to say that you
我想匹配字符串的结尾 或者技术上来说就在换行符之前
want to match the end of the string, or technically just before the newline
在字符串的末尾
at the end of the string.
但出于所有意图和目的 请将插入符号视为“开始”的意思
But for all intents and purposes, think of caret as meaning "start
字符串”和$符号表示“字符串结束” “
of the string" and $ sign as meaning "end of the string."
这是一个奇怪的事情 一个是插入符号 一个是$符号
It is a weird thing that one is a caret and one is $ sign.
这些并不是我认为是对立的东西
These are not really things that I think of as opposites,
比如括号之类的
like a parentheses or something like that.
但这些是世界多年前选择的象征
But those are the symbols the world chose many years ago.
现在让我们回到VS Code
So let me go back to VS Code now.
让我把这个特性添加到我的代码中
And let me add this feature to my code here.
让我指定 是的 我确实想搜索这个模式
Let me specify that yes, I do want to search for this pattern,
但我希望用户的输入以这种模式开始
but I want the user's input to start with this pattern
以这种模式结束
and end with this pattern.
所以即使它开始看起来更加神秘
So even though it's going to start looking even more cryptic,
我在开头放了一个插入符号
I put a caret symbol here at the beginning,
我在最后放了个$
and I put a $ sign here at the end.
这并不意味着我希望用户键入插入符号或$符号
That does not mean I want the user to type a caret symbol or a $ sign.
这是一种特殊的符号系统 表示re.search
This is special symbology that indicates to re.search
它现在应该只寻找与这个模式完全匹配的
that it should only look for now an exact match against this pattern.
如果我现在回到终端窗口
So if I now go back to my terminal window--
我会把之前的结果留在屏幕上
and I'll leave the previous result on the screen--
让我输入同样的内容
let me type the exact same thing.
“我的电子邮件地址malan@harvard.edu” 输入--
"My email address malan@harvard.edu," Enter--
抱歉 句号
sorry, period.
现在我要按回车键了
And now I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
现在这被认为是无效的
Now that's considered invalid.
但让我把屏幕清空
But let me clear the screen.
为了确保我没有弄坏东西
And just to make sure I didn't break things,
让我只输入我的电子邮件地址 这也是有效的
let me type in just my email address, and that, too, is valid.
现在关于我的正则表达式的这个版本的任何问题 请注意
Any questions now on this version of my regular expression, which, note,
更进一步 甚至更精确地指定
goes further to specify even more precisely
我希望它在开始和结束时都是匹配的？
that I want it to match at the start and the end?
对这个有什么问题吗？
Any questions on this one here?
观众：好的
AUDIENCE: OK.
你有斜杠 .edu 然后是$符号
You have slash, and .edu, then the $ sign.
但是点是正则表达式中的一个 对吗？
But the dot is one of the regular expression, right?
大卫·马兰：通常是这样的
DAVID MALAN: It normally is.
但我在这里之前故意加的这个反斜杠
But this backslash that I deliberately put before this period here
是一个逃逸的角色
is an escape character.
这是一种告诉re.earch我不想要任何字符的方式
It is a way of telling re.search that I don't want any character there,
我真的想在那里待上一段时间
I literally want a period there.
这是你区分它们的唯一方法
And it's the only way you can distinguish one from the other.
如果我去掉那个斜杠 这将意味着电子邮件地址
If I got rid of that slash, this would mean that the email address just
必须以任何字符结尾 然后是E 然后是D
has to end with any character, then an E, then a D,
而不是U 我不想那样
than a U. I don't want that.
我想要一个句点 然后是E 然后是D 然后是U
I want literally a period, then the E, then the D, then the U.
这实际上是一般编程和技术中的常见约定
This is actually common convention in programming and technology in general.
如果你和我决定一个大会
If you and I decide on a convention, whereby
我们正在使用键盘上的一些字符来表示一些特殊的东西
we're using some character on the keyboard to mean something special,
我们总是给自己制造未来的问题
invariably we create a future problem for ourself
当我们想要字面上使用相同的字符
when we want to literally use that same character.
因此 这个问题的总体解决方案
And so the solution in general to that problem
就是以某种方式逃避角色 这样计算机就能清楚地看到
is to somehow escape the character so that it's clear to the computer
它不是那个特殊的符号 而是它所看到的符号
that it's not that special symbol, it's literally the symbol it sees.
观众：所以我们甚至不知道--我们不需要在美元之前再进行一次削减
AUDIENCE: So we don't even know the-- we don't need another slash before the $
签字？
sign?
大卫·马兰：没有
DAVID MALAN: No.
因为在这种情况下 $sign意味着一些特别的东西
Because in this case, $ sign means something special.
根据这张图表 $符号本身并不意味着美元或货币
Per this chart here, $ sign by itself does not mean US dollars or currency.
字面意思是“匹配字符串的末尾”
It literally means "match the end of the string."
但是 如果我想让用户直接在结尾处键入$sign
If, however, I wanted the user to literally type in $ sign at the end
对于他们的投入 解决方案将是相同的
of their input, the solution would be the same.
我会在$符号前加一个反斜杠
I would put a backslash before the $ sign,
也就是说 我的电子邮件地址必须是类似maran@atherard.edu的地址
which means my email address would have to be something like malan@harvard.edu
$符号 这显然也是不正确的
$ sign, which is obviously not correct too.
所以反斜杠只是允许你告诉计算机不要处理
So backslash is just allow you to tell the computer to not treat
特别是那些符号 喜欢表达特殊的意思
those symbols specially, likes meaning something special,
而是逐字逐句地对待他们
but to treat them literally instead.
这里还有一个关于正则表达式的问题怎么样？
How about one other question here on regular expressions?
观众：你说过一代表加一
AUDIENCE: You said one represents to make it one plus,
然后你说一个是让它一无所有
then you said one was to make it one with nothing.
大卫·马兰：当然
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
观众：那你为什么要加上加号呢？
AUDIENCE: So why would you add the plus?
大卫·马兰：让我时光倒流
DAVID MALAN: Let me rewind in time.
我想你指的是我们早期的一个版本
I think what you're referring to was one of our earlier versions
这最初看起来是这样的 这只是意味着零或更多
that initially looked like this, which just meant zero or more
字符 而不是@符号 然后是零个或多个其他字符
characters, than an @ sign, then zero or more other characters.
然后我们进化成这样 两边都有点加 这
We then evolved to that to be this, dot plus on both sides, which
表示左侧的一个或多个字符 则
means one or more characters on the left, then
@符号 然后是右侧的一个或多个字符
an @ sign, then one or more characters on the right.
如果我对你的问题的理解正确的话
And if I'm interpreting your question correctly,
我之前提到的一点是 如果不使用加号或忘记
one of the points I made earlier was that if you didn't use plus or forgot
它的存在 你可以用两个相同的结果
that it exists, you could equivalently achieve the exact same result with two
点和* 因为第一个点表示任何字符--
dots and a *, because the first dot means any character--
它肯定在那里--
it's got to be there--
第二个点*表示零个或多个其他字符
the second dot * means zero or more other characters,
右边也一样
and same on the right.
所以这只是表达相同观点的另一种方式
So it's just another way of expressing the same idea.
“一个或多个”可以这样用点*表示
"One or more" can be represented like this with dot dot *,
或者 您可以使用更方便的点+语法 它的意思是相同的
or you can just use the handier syntax of dot +, which means the same thing.
好的
All right.
所以我敢说 这个正则表达式仍然存在一些问题
So I daresay there's still some problems with the regular expression in this
当前表单 因为即使现在我们开始寻找用户
current form, because even though now we're starting to look for the user
来自用户的字符串开头的名称
name at the beginning of the string from the user,
我们要从字面上寻找用户字符串末尾的.edu
and we're looking for the .edu literally at the end of the string from the user,
这些点现在有点太笼统了
those dots are a little too encompassing right now.
我被允许输入不止一个@符号
I'm allowed to type in more than the single @ sign.
为什么？
Why?
因为@是一个字符 点表示任何字符
Because @ is a character, and dot means any character.
所以老实说 我现在可以在这件事上想要多少@符号就有多少
So honestly, I can have as many @ signs in this thing at the moment as I want.
例如 如果我运行valiate.py的python
For instance, if I run python of validate.py,
Maran@atherard.edu仍然像预期的那样工作
malan@harvard.edu, still works as expected.
但是 如果我还运行validate.py的python 并且不正确地这样做
But if I also run python of validate.py and incorrectly do
应该是无效的 但它被认为是有效的
malan@@@harvard.edu, should be invalid, but it's considered valid instead.
因此 我认为当涉及到那个点时 我们需要更多地限制
So I think we need to be a little more restrictive when it comes to that dot.
我们不能只说 哦 任何一个老角色都很好
And we can't just say, oh, any old character there is fine.
我们需要更具体一些
We need to be more specific.
事实证明 正则表达式也支持这种语法
Well, it turns out that regular expressions also support this syntax.
您可以在图案内使用方括号
You can use square brackets inside of your pattern,
在这些方括号内包括一个或多个字符
and inside of those square brackets include one or more characters
你想要特别寻找的东西
that you want to look for specifically.
或者 您可以在这些方括号内
Alternatively, you can inside of those square brackets
加一个插入符号 不幸的是 在这里
put a caret symbol, which unfortunately in this context,
意思与“匹配字符串的开头”完全不同
means something completely different from "match the start of the string."
但这将是方括号内的补码运算符
But this would be the complement operator inside of the square brackets,
这意味着“你不能匹配这些字符中的任何一个 ”
which means "you cannot match any of these characters."
因此 事情现在看起来更神秘了
So things are about to look even more cryptic now.
但这就是为什么我们在这里关注正则表达式本身的原因
But that's why we're focusing on regular expressions on their own here.
如果我不想允许任何字符 这就是点 让我继续
If I don't want to allow any character, which is what a dot is, let me go ahead
我可以说 我只想支持A、B、C或D
and I could just say, well, I only want to support A, or Bs, or Cs, or Ds,
或者ES 或者F 或者Gs
or Es, or Fs, or Gs.
我可以在这里输入整个字母表 外加一些数字
I could type in the whole alphabet here plus some numbers
将我想要允许的所有字母都包括在内
to actually include all of the letters that I do want to allow.
但老实说 这样会更简单一些
But honestly, a little simpler would be this.
我可以使用^符号 然后使用@符号 这样做的效果是
I could use a ^ symbol and then an @ sign, which has the effect of saying,
这是一组字符 除了@符号外 其他字符都有
this is the set of characters that has everything except an @ sign.
我在这里也可以做同样的事情
And I can do the same thing over here.
我可以做左方括号^ @符号 而不是@符号右边的圆点
Instead of a dot to the right of the @ sign, I can do open bracket ^, @ sign.
我承认 这里的局势开始迅速升级
And I admit, things are starting to escalate quickly here,
但让我们从左边开始 再到右边
but let's start from the left and go to the right.
在字符串开头的方括号外
This ^ outside of the square brackets at the very start of my string,
与前面一样 表示“从字符串的开头匹配” “
as before, means "match from the start of the string."
让我们跳到前面
And let's jump ahead.
正则表达式末尾的$符号表示“匹配
The $ sign all the way at the end of the regular expression means "match
在字符串的末尾 “
at the end of the string."
所以如果我们能在心里把这些简单明了地勾出来
So if we can mentally tick those off as straightforward, let's
现在把注意力集中在中间的其他东西上
now focus on everything else in the middle.
左边是新的语法
Well, to the left here we have new syntax--
一个方括号 另一个^ 一个@符号和一个封闭的方括号 然后
a square bracket, another ^, an @ sign, and a closed square bracket, and then
a +.
“+”的意思和往常一样
The + means the same thing as always.
意思是“左边的一个或多个东西 “
It means "one or more of the things to the left."
左边的是什么？
What is the thing to the left?
这是新的语法
Well, this is the new syntax.
在方括号里 我有一个^符号和一个@符号
Inside of square brackets here, I have a ^ symbol and then an @ sign.
这意味着除了@符号之外的任何字符
That just means any character except an @ sign.
这是一个奇怪的语法 但这就是我们如何表达这个简单的想法--
It's a weird syntax, but this is how we can express that simple idea--
键盘上除@符号以外的任何字符
any character on the keyboard except for an @ sign.
而且 即使是那些不在你键盘上的字符
And heck, even other characters that aren't physically on your keyboard
但仍然存在
but that nonetheless exist.
然后我们有一个字面上的@符号 然后我们有另一个同样的东西--
Then we have a literal @ sign, then we have another one of these same things--
方括号 ^@闭括号 表示除@符号以外的任何字符
square bracket, ^@ closed bracket, which means any character except an @ sign,
然后是其中的一个或多个 后面跟着一个句号edu
then one or more of those things, followed by literally a period edu.
现在让我再做一次
So now let me go ahead and do this again.
让我试试validate.py的python并测试我自己的电子邮件地址
Let me rerun python of validate.py and test my own email address
确保我没有把事情搞得更糟
to make sure I've not made things worse.
我们很好
And we're good.
现在让我继续清理屏幕 运行validate.py的python
Now let me go ahead and clear my screen and run python of validate.py
再次做harvard.edu 这次我交叉手指
again and do malan@@@harvard.edu, crossing my fingers this time.
最后 这是无效的
And finally, this now is invalid.
为什么要这样？
Why?
我允许自己在用户输入的中间有一个@符号
I'm allowing myself to have one @ sign in the middle of the user's input,
但是按照这个新语法 左边的所有东西都不能是@符号
but everything to the left per this new syntax cannot be an @ sign.
它可以是任何东西 但一次或多次
It can be anything but one or more times.
符号右边的任何东西都可以不是符号
And everything to the right of the @ sign can be anything but an @ sign one
或者更多次 最后是字面上的.edu
or more times followed by, lastly, a literal .edu.
所以 新的语法很简单 就是--
So again, the new syntax is quite simply this--
方括号允许您指定一组您按字面意思
square brackets allow you to specify a set of characters that you literally
在键盘上打字--
type out at your keyboard--
A B C D E F 或补语 相反
A, B, C, D, E, F, or the complement, the opposite,
^符号 意思是“不” 然后一个或多个符号
the ^ symbol, which means "not," and then the one or more symbols you
想要排除
want to exclude.
这里有关于这个语法的问题吗？
Questions now on this syntax here?
观众：那么 在@sign之后 我们可以用花括号来表示吗
AUDIENCE: So right after @ sign, can we use the curly brackets m one
这样我们就只能重复一次@符号了？
so that we can only have one repetition of the @ symbol?
大卫·马兰：当然
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely.
所以我们可以这么做
So we could do this.
让我继续下去 开始VS Code
Let me go ahead and pull up VS Code.
让我删除正则表达式的当前形式
And let me delete the current form of a regular expression
回到我们开始的地方 那只是点*@和点*
and go back to where we began, which was just dot * @ and dot *.
我完全可以做这样的事
I could absolutely do something like this
并要求我在这里至少要有一个角色
and require that I want at least one of any character here.
然后我可以做更多的事情来拥有更多的东西
And then I could do something more to have any more as well.
我们在前面的幻灯片中看到了花括号的语法
So the curly brace syntax, which we saw on the slide earlier
但还没用过 绝对可以用
but didn't yet use, absolutely can be used
若要指定特定的字符数 请执行以下操作
to specify a specific number of characters.
但老实说 这比必要的更冗长
But honestly, this is more verbose than is necessary.
最好的解决方案 可以说 或者至少是最简单的
The best solution, arguably, or the simplest, at least,
归根结底 就是点+
ultimately, is just to say dot +.
但是 还有另一个你可以解决同样问题的例子
But there, too, another example of how you can solve the same problem
多方面的
multiple ways.
让我们回到刚才正则表达式所在的位置
Let me go back to where the regular expression just was
并回答其他问题
and take other questions as well.
关于角色集的问题还是补充集的问题？
Questions on the sets of characters or complementing that set?
观众：那么你能用同样的语法吗？
AUDIENCE: So can you use that same syntax
说你不想让某个特定的字符贯穿整个字符串？
to say that you don't want a certain character throughout the whole string?
大卫·马兰：你可以
DAVID MALAN: You could.
这将会是--
It's going to be--
你完全可以使用相同的字符来排除--
you could absolutely use the same character to exclude--
您完全可以使用此语法来排除某个字符
you could absolutely use this syntax to exclude a certain character
从整个字符串中
from the entire string.
但现在就有点难了
But it would be a little harder right now,
因为我们仍然需要.edu结尾
because we're still requiring .edu the end.
但是 是的 绝对的
But yes, absolutely.
其他问题？
Other questions?
观众：如果用户在开始时输入.edu会发生什么
AUDIENCE: What happens if the user inputs .edu in the beginning
的字符串？
of the string?
大卫·马兰：问得好
DAVID MALAN: A good question.
如果用户在字符串的开头输入.edu 会发生什么？
What happens if the user types in .edu at the beginning of the string?
让我们回到VS Code
Well, let me go back to VS Code here.
让我们试着用两种不同的方法来解决这个问题
And let's try to solve this in two different ways.
首先 让我们看看正则表达式
First, let's look at the regular expression
看看我们是否能推断出这是否是可以容忍的
and see if we can infer if that's going to be tolerated.
根据当前的神秘正则表达式
Well, according to the current cryptic regular expression,
我是说你可以有任何字符除了@符号
I'm saying that you can have any character except the @ sign.
所以我可以 可能是教育部的点
So that would work I. Could have the dot for the .edu.
但是我必须有一个@符号
But then I have to have an @ sign.
所以这是行不通的 因为如果我只是输入.edu
So that wouldn't really work, because if I'm just typing in .edu,
我们不会越过这个限制
we're not going to pass that constraint.
现在让我运行这个程序
So now let me try this by running the program.
让我按字面意思输入. edu
Let me type in just literally .edu.
这不管用
That doesn't work.
但是 但是 但是我可以这样做 .edu@. edu
But, but, but I could do this, .edu@.edu.
这也是无效的
That, too, is invalid.
但让我这样做 . edu@something.edu
But let me do this, .edu@something.edu.
那就过去了
That passes.
所以现在开始有点奇怪了
So it's starting to get a little weird now.
可能有效 也可能无效
Maybe it's valid, maybe it's not.
但我认为我们最终也会更精确
But I think we'll eventually be more precise, too.
再问一个关于这个正则表达式的问题怎么样
How about one more question on this regular expression
这些集合的互补呢？
and these complementing of sets?
观众：我们可以用另一个域名 字符串输入吗？
AUDIENCE: Can we use another domain name, the string input?
大卫·马兰：你能用别的域名吗？
DAVID MALAN: Can you use another domain name?
当然了
Absolutely.
我用我自己的只是为了演示
I'm using my own just for the sake of demonstration.
但你绝对可以使用任何域或顶级域
But you could absolutely use any domain or top-level domain.
我使用的是.edu 它非常以美国为中心
And I'm using .edu, which is very US centric.
但这对任何顶级域都是完全一样的
But this would absolutely work exactly the same for any top-level domain.
好吧
All right.
现在让我继续下去 并建议我们改进这个正则表达式
Let me go ahead now and propose that we improve this regular expression
因为如果我在VS Code中再次调用它
further, because if I pull it up again in VS Code here,
你会发现我还是有点太宽容了
you'll see that I'm being a little too tolerant still.
原来对某人的用户名是有一定要求的
It turns out that there are certain requirements for someone's username
和电子邮件地址中的域名
and domain name in an email address.
电子邮件地址可以是什么在世界上有一个官方标准
There is an official standard in the world for what an email address can be
以及里面可以有哪些角色
and what characters can be in it.
这对所有的角色来说都太过通融了
And this is way too accommodating of all the characters
在这个世界上除了@符号
in the world except for the @ symbol.
所以让我们来缩小一下定义
So let's actually narrow the definition of what
我们将容忍用户名
we're going to tolerate in usernames.
像Gmail这样的公司当然也可以做到这一点
And companies like Gmail could certainly do this as well.
假设不只是我想要排除@sign
Suppose that it's not just that I want to exclude @ sign.
假设我只想考虑 比方说
Suppose that I only want to allow for, say,
通常出现在单词中的字符
characters that normally appear in words,
就像字母表中的字母 从A到Z 无论是大写还是小写
like letters of the alphabet, A through z, be it uppercase or lowercase,
也许有些数字 见鬼 甚至下划线也可以被允许
maybe some numbers, and heck, maybe even an underscore could be allowed, too.
我们可以使用相同的方括号语法
Well, we can use this same square bracket syntax
要指定一组字符 请如下所示
to specify a set of characters as follows.
我可以做abc定义--
I could do abcdefghij--
天哪
oh, my god.
这将耗费很长时间
This is going to take forever.
我要把字母表中的26个字母全部打出来
I'm going to have to type out all 26 letters of the alphabet,
小写和大写都是
both lowercase and uppercase.
所以让我别再这么做了
So let me stop doing that.
已经有更好的办法了
There's a better way already.
如果要在这些方括号中指定字母范围
If you want to specify within these square brackets a range of letters,
实际上 您可以只使用连字符
you can actually just do a hyphen.
如果你真的在这些方括号里做a-z
If you literally do a-z in these square brackets,
计算机会知道你的意思是从a到z
the computer is going to know you mean a through z.
你不需要打字母表中的26个字母
You do not need to type 26 letters of the alphabet.
如果您还想包含大写字母 只需执行相同的操作
If you want to include uppercase letters as well, you just do the same.
没有空格 没有逗号 你只需通过大写Z输入a即可
No spaces, no commas, you literally just keep typing a through capital Z.
所以我有一个小连字符 小z 大A连字符
So I have little a hyphen little z, big A hyphen
大Z 没有空格 没有逗号 没有分隔符
big Z. No spaces, no commas, no separators.
您只需不断指定这些范围即可
You just keep specifying those ranges.
如果我还想要数字 我可以做01234--
If I additionally want numbers, I could do 01234--
没有
nope.
您不需要输入所有10位十进制数字
You don't need to type in all 10 decimal digits.
您也可以使用连字符来表示0到9
You can just say 0 through 9 using a hyphen as well.
如果您现在想要支持下划线
And if you now want to support underscores
同样 这在电子邮件地址的用户名中也很常见
as well, which is pretty common in usernames for email addresses,
从字面上看 你只需在结尾处输入下划线
you can literally just type an underscore at the end.
请注意 所有这些字符都在里面
Notice that all of these characters are inside
的方括号 这再次意味着这里是一组字符
of square brackets, which just again, means here is a set of characters
这是我想允许的
that I want to allow.
我没有在整件事的开头使用^符号
I have not used a ^ symbol at the beginning of this whole thing,
因为我不想补充它--用E来补充它
because I don't want to complement it-- complement it with an E,
而不是用我来恭维--
not compliment it with an I--
我不想通过把它变成相反的东西来补充它
I don't want to complement it by making it the opposite.
我真的只想接受这些角色
I literally want to accept only these characters.
我将继续在右边做同样的事情
I'm going to go ahead and do the same thing on the right.
如果我想要求域名类似
If I want to require that the domain name similarly
来自这组人物 诚然有点太窄了
come from this set of characters, which admittedly is a little too narrow,
但它现在很熟悉 所以我们就简单点
but it's familiar for now so we'll keep it simple,
我将继续在那里粘贴完全相同的一组字符
I'm going to go ahead and paste that exact same set of characters over there
往右走
to the right.
因此 现在 它的限制要严格得多
And so now, it's much more restrictive.
现在 我将继续运行valiate.py的python
Now I'm going to go ahead and run python of validate.py.
我要测试一下我自己的电子邮件地址 我们还是可以的
I'm going to test my own email address, and we're still good.
我要清空屏幕 再运行一次
I'm going to clear my screen and run it once more,
这一次 它试图打破它
this time trying to break it.
让我继续做一些事情 比如 david_maran@atherard.edu
Let me go ahead and do something like, how about, david_malan@harvard.edu,
进入 但这也将是有效的
Enter, but that, too, is going to be valid.
但如果我再做一件完全错误的事
But if I do something completely wrong again,
就像Malan@atherard.edu一样 这仍然是无效的
like malan@@@harvard.edu, that's still going to be invalid.
为什么？
Why?
因为我的正则表达式当前只允许
Because my regular expression currently only allows
对于中间的一个@ 因为所有东西都在左边
for a single @ in the middle, because everything to the left
必须是字母数字--
must be alphanumeric--
字母或数字--或下划线
alphabetical or numeric-- or an underscore,
同样的东西在右边 后面跟着.edu
the same thing to the right, followed by the .edu.
老实说 这是一个正则表达式
Now honestly, this is a regular expression
你可能养成了在现实世界打字的习惯
that you might be in the habit of typing in the real world.
尽管这看起来很神秘 但这是正则表达式的世界
As cryptic as this might look, this is the world of regular expressions.
因此 随着时间的推移 您会越来越熟悉这种语法
So you'll get more comfortable with this syntax over time.
但值得庆幸的是 其中一些模式是
But thankfully, some of these patterns are
如此常见 以至于有内置的快捷键来表示
so common that there are built-in shortcuts for representing
一些相同的信息
some of the same information.
这就是说 您不必不断地输入所有的符号
That is to say, you don't have to constantly type out all of the symbols
你想要包括的 因为很有可能是其他程序员
that you want to include, because odds are some other programmer
也遇到了同样的问题
has had the same problem.
因此内置到正则表达式本身
So built into regular expressions themselves
下面是一些您可以使用的其他模式
are some additional patterns you can use.
事实上 我可以继续下去 去掉这一整套 从a到z
And in fact, I can go ahead and get rid of this entire set, a through z
小写 A到Z大写 0到9和一个下划线
lowercase, A through Z uppercase, 0 through 9 and an underscore,
只需将其替换为单个反斜杠w
and just replace it with a single backslash w.
在这种情况下 反斜杠w表示“单词字符”
Backslash w in this case represents a "word character,"
通常称为字母数字符号或下划线
which is commonly known as a alphanumeric symbol or the underscore
也是
as well.
我要在这里做同样的事情
I'm going to do the same thing over here.
我将突出显示整组方括号
I'm going to highlight the entire set of square brackets,
删除它 并将其替换为一个反斜杠w
delete it, and replace it with a single backslash w.
现在我觉得我们正在取得进展
And now I feel like we're making progress,
因为即使它是神秘的 而且会
because even though it's cryptic, and would have
看起来有点神秘--
looked way cryptic a little bit ago--
尽管现在它看起来会更神秘一点
and even though it would have looked even more cryptic a little bit ago, now
它至少开始读起来更友好了一点
it's at least starting to read a little more friendly.
左边的^表示“从字符串的开头开始匹配”
This ^ on the left means "start matching at the beginning of the string."
反斜杠w表示“任何单词字符”
Backslash w means "any word character."
+的意思是“一个或多个”
The + means "one or more."
@字面上的符号
@ symbol literally.
然后是另一个单词字符 一个或多个 然后是字面点 然后是
Then another word character, one or more. then a literal dot, then
字面意思是edu 然后在字符串的最末端进行匹配 就是这样
literally edu, and then match at the very end of the string, and that's it.
因此 还有更多这样的东西
So there's more of these, too.
我们不会在这里全部使用它们 但这里是
And we won't use them all here, but here is
可以在正则表达式中使用的模式的部分列表
a partial list of the patterns you can use within a regular expression.
第一 任何十进制数字都有反斜杠d “十进制数字”的意思是
One, you have backslash d for any decimal digit, "decimal digit" meaning
0到9
0 through 9.
在这里 通常也会这样做 如果你想做相反的事情
Commonly done here, too, is if you want to do the opposite of that,
补码 可以说 你可以做反斜杠大写D 这是
the complement, so to speak, you can do backslash capital D, which
不是十进制数字的任何数字
is anything that's not a decimal digit.
所以它可能是字母、标点符号 也可能是其他符号
So it might be letters, and punctuation, and other symbols as well.
同时 反斜杠S表示空格字符
Meanwhile, backslash s means whitespace characters,
比如按一下空格键 或者按键盘上的Tab键
like a single hit of the space, or maybe hitting Tab on the keyboard.
那是空格
That's whitespace.
反斜杠大写S是反义词或补语
Backslash capital S is the opposite or complement
任何不是空格的字符
of that-- anything that's not a whitespace character.
我们已经看到 反斜杠w是一个单词字符 以及
Backslash w, we've seen, a word character, as well as
数字和下划线
numbers and the underscore.
如果你想要与之互补或相反的
And if you want the complement or opposite of that,
您可以使用反斜杠大写W来表示除单词字符以外的所有字符
you can use backslash capital W to give you everything but a word character.
再说一次 这些都是常见的模式 想必很多人都是
Again, these are just common patterns that so many people were presumably
使用在过去 它现在被烘焙到正则表达式语法
using in yesteryear that it's now baked into the regular expression syntax
这样你就可以更简洁地表达你同样的想法
so that you can more succinctly express your same ideas.
那么 对这种方法有什么问题吗
Any questions, then, on this approach here,
我们现在用反斜杠w来表示我的单词字符？
where we're now using backslash w to represent my word character?
观众：所以我想问的是
AUDIENCE: So what I want to ask about was
这个--实际上是前面的方法 就像方括号的方法
the-- actually the previous approach, like the square bracket approach.
我们可以在那里收单子吗？
Could we accept lists in there?
大卫·马兰：是的
DAVID MALAN: Yes.
我们很快就会看到这一点
We'll see this before long.
但假设你不仅想容忍.edu 而且还想容忍.edu或.com
But suppose you wanted to tolerate not just .edu, but maybe .edu, or .com,
你可以做到的
you could do this.
你可以引入圆括号 然后你可以把它们放在一起
You could introduce parentheses, and then you can or those together.
我可以说com或edu
I could say com or edu.
也可以添加一些东西 如在美国 或政府 或网络
Could also add in something like in the US, or gov, or net,
或其他任何东西 或组织 或诸如此类
or anything else, or org, or the like.
这里的每一条竖线都意味着一些特别的东西
And each of the vertical bars here means something special.
意思是“或”
It means "or."
而圆括号只是简单地将事物组合在一起
And the parentheses simply group things together.
形式上 你在这里有这样的语法--
Formally, you have this syntax here--
A或B A或竖线B 意思是“A必须匹配或B必须匹配 ”
A or B, A or vertical bar B, means "A has to match or B has to match,"
其中A和B可以是您想要的任何其他图案
where A and B can be any other patterns you want.
在括号中 您可以将这些内容组合在一起
In parentheses, you can group those things together.
因此 就像数学一样 你可以把想法组合成一个短语
So just like math, you can combine ideas into one phrase
做这件事或做那件事
and do this thing or the other.
还有其他语法 我们很快就会看到
And there's other syntax as well that we'll soon see.
这里还有关于这些正则表达式和此语法的其他问题吗？
Other questions on these regular expressions and this syntax here?
观众：如果我们在表达式中加入空格呢？
AUDIENCE: What if we put spaces in the expression?
大卫·马兰：当然
DAVID MALAN: Sure.
所以如果你想在里面加空格 你不能只用反斜杠w
So if you want spaces in there, you can't use backslash w alone,
因为这只是一个单词字符 它是字母 数字
because that is only a word character which is alphabetical, numerical,
或下划线
or the underscore.
但你能做到的
But you could do this.
您可以回到使用方括号的这种方法
You could go back to this approach whereby you use square brackets.
你可以说a到z 或者A到Z 或者0到9
And you could say a through z, or A through Z, or 0 through 9,
或者下划线 或者我按空格键 一个空格
or underscore, or I'm going to hit the space bar, a single space.
你可以在方括号内放一个空格
You can put a literal space inside of the square brackets, which
会让你发现一个空间
will allow you then to detect a space.
或者 我仍然可以使用反斜杠w
Alternatively, I could still use backslash w,
但我可以把它结合起来
But I could combine it as follows.
我可以说 给我一个反斜杠W或反斜杠S
I could say, give me a backslash w or a backslash s,
因为回想一下 反斜杠s是空格
because recall that backslash s is whitespace.
所以它不仅仅是一个空间
So it's even more than a single space.
可能是账单
It could be a tab.
但是把这些放在括号里
But by putting those things in parentheses, now
你可以把左边的东西
you can match either the thing on the left
或右边的东西一次或多次
or the thing on the right one or more times.
关于这些正则表达式的另一个问题怎么样？
How about one other question on these regular expressions?
观众：完美
AUDIENCE: Perfect.
所以我想问 反斜杠w中是否包含一个点？
So I was going to ask, does the backslash w include a dot?
因为-不 好吧
Because-- no, OK.
大卫·马兰：不 它只包括字母、数字和下划线
DAVID MALAN: No, it only Includes letters, numbers, and underscore.
到此为止
That is it.
观众：我想知道 你举了一个例子
AUDIENCE: And I was wondering, you gave an example
开始的时候有空格 比如这是我的邮箱 某某
at the beginning that had spaces, like this is my email, so-and-so.
我不认为我们现在的版本
I don't think our current version--
甚至很久以前就不再接受它了
or even quite a long while ago stopped accepting it.
这是因为^还是因为别的什么？
Was that because of the ^ or because of something else?
大卫·马兰：不 我之所以在其他英语单词中处理空格
DAVID MALAN: No, the reason I was handling spaces in other English words
当我输入我的电子邮件地址malan@harvard.edu时
when I typed out my email address as malan@harvard.edu
是因为我们最初使用的是点 * 或点+ 这是任何字符
was because we were using initially dot *, or dot +, which is any character.
即使在那之后 我们也说了除了“标志”之外的任何话
And even after that, we said anything except the @ sign,
其中包括空格
which includes spaces.
只有一次我开始使用方括号和a到z和
Only once I started using square brackets and a through z and 0
到9和下划线 我们终于说到重点了吗？
through 9 and underscore did we finally get to the point
在那里我们会拒绝空白
where we would reject white space.
事实上 我可以在这里运行这个
And in fact, I can run this here.
让我来看看VS Code中我的代码的当前版本 它再次使用
Let me go into the current version of my code in VS Code, which is using, again,
反斜杠w代表单词字符 让
the backslash w's for word characters, let
我运行了valiate.py的python 并错误地键入了一些内容
me run python of validate.py and incorrectly type in something
就像“我的电子邮件地址是maran@atherard.edu”一样 句号
like "my email address is malan@harvard.edu," period, which
我的用户名左侧有空格 现在无效
has spaces to the left of my username, and that is now invalid,
因为空格不是一个单词字符
because space is not a word character.
你也会注意到 从技术上讲 我不允许使用圆点
You're going to notice, too, that technically I'm not allowing dots.
你们中的一些人可能会想 等一下
And some of you might be thinking, wait a minute.
我的Gmail地址里有一个圆点
My Gmail address has a dot in it.
这是我们仍然需要解决的问题
That's something we're going to still have to fix.
反斜杠w不是这里的结束
A backslash w is not the end all here.
它只是让我们表达我们之前的解决方案
It's just allowing us to express our previous solution
简明扼要一点
a little more succinctly.
现在 有一件事我们还没有处理好
Now, one thing we're still not handling quite properly
是大写还是小写
is uppercase versus lowercase.
从技术上讲 反斜杠w可以处理小写字母和大写字母
The backslash w technically does handle lowercase letters and uppercase,
因为它和之前的场景一模一样
because it's the exact same thing as that set from before,
从小A到小Z 从大A到大Z 但看这个
which had little a through little z and big A through big Z. But watch this.
让我继续以我当前的形式运行valiate.py的python
Let me go ahead in my current form run python of validate.py,
就因为我的大写锁钥匙掉了 maran@atherard.edu
and just because my Caps lock key is down, MALAN@HARVARD.EDU,
喊着我的电子邮件地址
shouting my email address.
就马兰而言 一切都会好起来的
It's going to be OK in terms of the MALAN.
就哈佛大学而言 一切都会好起来的
It's going to be OK in terms of the HARVARD,
因为这些字符与反斜杠w匹配
because those are matching the backslash w, which
不包括小写和大写
does include lowercase and uppercase.
但我要看到的是残废
But I'm about to see invalid.
为什么？
Why?
为什么在这里全部大写的时候 maran@greavard.edu是无效的
Why is MALAN@HARVARD.EDU invalid when it's in all caps here,
即使我用的是反斜杠w？
even though I'm using backslash w?
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
所以您要求的是小写的domain.edu
So you are asking for the domain.edu in lowercase,
而且你是用大写字母打字的
and you're typing it in uppercase.
大卫·马兰：没错
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
我用大写字母输入我的电子邮件地址
I'm typing in my email address in all uppercase,
但我在找字面上的“.edu”
but I'm looking for literally ".edu."
当我看到你们戴着AirPods和你们中的许多人戴着耳机
And as I see you with AirPods and so many of you with headphones,
我很抱歉刚才对着我的麦克风大喊大叫来表达这一点
I apologize for yelling into my microphone just now to make this point.
但让我们看看我们是否能解决这个问题
But let's see if we can't fix that.
好吧 如果我在第5行的模式是希望它是小写的
Well, if my pattern on line 5 is expecting it to be lowercase,
事实上 我有几种方法可以解决这个问题
there's actually a few ways I can solve this.
一种是我们以前见过的东西
One would be something we've seen before.
我可以强制用户的输入全部为小写
I could just force the user's input to all lowercase.
我可以把我的第一行的末尾 更低 并实际上强制它
And I could put onto the end of my first line .lower and actually force it all
转换为小写
to lowercase.
或者 我可以稍晚一点再这样做
Alternatively, I could do that a little later.
我可以不传递电子邮件 而是传递电子邮件的小写版本
Instead of passing an email, I could pass in the lowercase version of email,
因为电子邮件地址实际上应该不区分大小写
because email addresses should, in fact, be case insensitive.
因此 这也会奏效
So that would work, too.
但这里还有另一种机制 值得一看
But there's another mechanism here, which is worth seeing.
事实证明 调用re.earch之前的函数支持、调用
It turns out that that function before called re.search supports, recall,
第三个论点也是 这些所谓的旗帜
a third argument as well, these so-called flags.
标志是配置选项 通常
And flags are configuration options, typically
对于一个函数 这允许您对其进行稍微不同的配置
to a function, that allow you to configure it a little differently.
我应该如何开始配置此呼叫
And how might I go about configuring this call
重新搜索稍微有些不同 因为我目前只通过
to re.search a little bit differently insofar as I'm currently only passing
在两次争论中？
in two arguments?
事实证明 您可以传递给此函数的一些标志
Well, it turns out that some of the flags you can pass into this function
是这些吗
are these.
事实证明 Python中的正则表达式库 也就是
It turns out that the regular expression library in Python, a.k.a.
Re 带有一些内置变量 可以说
re, comes with a few built-in variables, so to speak,
你可以认为是常量的东西
things that you can think of as constants,
有意义的东西重新搜索
that have meaning to re.search.
他们这样做的方式如下
And they do so as follows.
如果作为标志re.IGNORECASE传递 re.earch将执行什么操作
If you pass in as a flag re.IGNORECASE, what re.search is going to do
忽略用户输入的大小写
is ignore the case of the user's input.
它可以是大写、小写、它们的组合
It can be uppercase, lowercase, a combination thereof,
这起案件将被忽视
the case is going to be ignored.
它将被冷淡地对待
It will be treated case insensitively.
你还可以做其他我们在这里做不到的事情
And you can do other things, too, that we won't do here.
但是 如果您想要处理可能跨越多行的用户输入--
But if you want to handle the user's input that maybe spans multiple lines--
也许他们输入的不仅仅是一个电子邮件地址 而是一整段
maybe they didn't just type in an email address but an entire paragraph
如果你想匹配不同的行
of text, and you want to match different lines
有多行的文本
of that text that is multiple lines.
另一个标志是re.MULTILINE 或者re.DOTALL
Another flag is for re.MULTILINE for just that, or re.DOTALL,
你可以配置这个点
whereby you can configure the dot to recognize not just
除了换行符之外的任何字符 但也可以是任何字符加换行符
any character except newlines but any character plus newlines as well.
但现在 让我继续 只是利用这第一个
But for now, let me go ahead and just make use of this first one.
让我向re.search传递第三个参数 即re. IGNORECASE
Let me pass in a third argument to re.search, which is re.IGNORECASE.
现在让我在不清除
Let me now rerun the program without clearing
我的屏幕 python的validate.py
my screen, python of validate.py.
让我再次输入所有大写字母 有效地大喊
Let me type in again in all caps, effectively shouting,
MALAN@HARVARD.EDU 输入 现在它被认为是有效的
MALAN@HARVARD.EDU, Enter, and now it's considered valid,
因为我特别告诉re.search
because I'm telling re.search specifically
忽略输入的大小写
to ignore the case of the input.
在这里也可以
And that, too, here is fine.
为什么我可以使用这种方法而不是调用.lower
And why might I do this approach rather than call .lower in one of those other
地点？
locations?
呃 如果我不想改变用户的输入
Eh, if I don't actually want to change the user's input for whatever reason,
我仍然可以不加区分地对待它
I can still treat it case insensitively without actually changing
这个变量本身的值
the value of that variable itself.
好了 关于电子邮件地址的验证 现在还有什么问题吗？
All right, any final questions now on this validation of email addresses?
观众：所以模式是一个字符串 对吗？
AUDIENCE: So the pattern is a string, right?
大卫·马兰：嗯
DAVID MALAN: Mm-hmm.
观众：我们可以使用fstring吗？
AUDIENCE: Can we use an fstring?
大卫·马兰：你可以
DAVID MALAN: You can.
是的 你可以使用一个fstring 这样你就可以插入 例如
Yes, you can use an fstring so that you could plug in, for instance,
变量的值并将其传递给函数
the value of a variable and pass it into the function.
其他问题？
Other questions on this?
观众：反斜杠w字符 我们可以把它作为用户的输入吗？
AUDIENCE: Backslash w character, could we take it as an input from the user?
David Malan：技术上是的
DAVID MALAN: Technically yes.
这不是我们现在要解决的问题
That's not a problem we're trying to solve right now.
我们希望用户提供文字输入 比如他们的电子邮件地址
We want the user to provide literal input, like their email address,
不一定是正则表达式
not necessarily a regular expression.
但是你可以想象构建一个软件
But you could imagine building software that asks the user, especially
如果他们是更高级的用户 出于某种原因
if they're more advanced users, to type in a regular expression for some reason
来验证其他的东西
to validate something else against that.
事实上 这就是Google正在做的事情
And in fact, that's what Google is doing.
如果您尝试使用Google Forms并创建一个带有响应验证的表单
If you play around with Google Forms and create a form with response validation
并选择正则表达式 谷歌允许你和我输入
and select Regular Expression, Google lets you and I type
在我们自己的正则表达式中 这将是一个很好的例子
in our own regular expressions, which would be a perfect example of that.
好的
All right.
好吧 让我提议我们试着解决另一个问题
Well, let me propose that we try to solve one other problem here,
因此 如果我进入与之前相同的版本 现在忽略大小写
whereby if I go into the same version as before, which is now ignoring case,
但我输入了我的另一个电子邮件地址
but I type in one of my other email addresses.
让我继续运行valiate.py的python
Let me go ahead and run python of validate.py.
这一次 让我输入的不是maran@atherard.edu 它
And this time, let me type in not malan@harvard.edu, which
我主要使用的是另一个电子邮件地址
I use primarily, but another email address
我的 maran@cs50.atherard.edu 它转发到相同的
of mine, malan@cs50.harvard.edu, which forwards to the same.
现在让我继续按Enter键
Let me go ahead and hit Enter now.
嗯 无效 尽管我很确定
And huh, invalid, even though I'm pretty sure that
实际上 是我的电子邮件地址
is, in fact, my email address.
好吧 让我们来找出原因吧
Well, let's put our finger on the reason why.
为什么现在是maran@cs50.atherard.edu
Why at the moment is malan@cs50.harvard.edu
被认为是无效的 即使我很确定我发送和接收
being considered invalid, even though I'm pretty sure I send and receive
也是从那个地址发的电子邮件吗？
email from that address, too?
为什么会这样呢？
Why might that be?
观众：因为在@符号后面有一个圆点
AUDIENCE: Because there is a dot that has come after the @ symbol.
大卫·马兰：没错
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
我的CS50后面有一个圆点
There's a dot after my cs50.
我并不期待那里有任何圆点 我只是期待
And I'm not expecting any dots there, I'm expecting only,
同样是单词字符 从A到z、0到9和下划线
again, word characters, which is A through z, 0 through 9, and underscore.
所以我得在这里重新装备一下
So I'm going to have to retool here.
但我怎么能着手做这件事呢？
But how could I go about doing this?
从理论上讲 可能还有其他电子邮件地址
Well, it turns out theoretically, there could be other email addresses,
例如 尽管它们会变得有点过长
even though they'd be getting a little excessively long, for instance,
Maran@omething.cs50.atherard.edu 技术上并不存在
malan@something.cs50.harvard.edu, which does not technically exist,
但这是可能的
but it could.
当然 你可以像我们在这里看到的那样 在一个域名中有多个圆点
You can have, of course, multiple dots in a domain name like we see here.
如果我们也能处理好那不是很好吗？
Wouldn't it be nice if we could handle that as well?
好吧 让我提议如下修改我的正则表达式
Well, let me propose that we modify my regular expression as follows.
事实证明 你可以把想法组合在一起
It turns out that you can group ideas together.
您不仅可以询问此模式是否匹配
And you can not only ask whether or not this pattern matches
或者这个使用类似A竖线B的语法 意思是“A或B”
or this one using syntax like A vertical bar B, which means "either A or B,"
您还可以将对象组合在一起 然后对其应用其他运算符
you can also group things together and then apply some other operator to them
也是
as well.
事实上 让我回到这里的代码
In fact, let me go back to the code here.
让我提议 如果我想容忍像cs50这样的子域
And let me propose that if I want to tolerate a subdomain, like cs50,
这可能在那里 也可能不在那里 让我继续进行更改 如下所示
that may or may not be there, let me go ahead and change it as follows.
我可以天真地做这件事
I could naively do this.
如果我想支持子域 我可以说 好吧
If I want to support subdomains, I could say, well,
让我们考虑其他单词字符加号 然后是字面点
let's allow for other word characters plus, and then a literal dot.
请注意 我将在这里用蓝色突出显示我刚刚添加的内容
And notice, I'll highlight in blue here what I've just added.
其他一切都是一样的 但我现在要为另一个序列添加空间
Everything else is the same, but I'm now adding room for another sequence of one
或更多单词字符 然后是字面点
or more word characters and then a literal dot.
所以现在 我想 如果我重新运行valiate.py的python
So this now, I think, if I rerun python of validate.py,
将适用于Malan@cs50.atherard.edu 输入
will work for malan@cs50.harvard.edu, Enter.
不幸的是 有没有人知道这是怎么回事？
Unfortunately, does anyone see where this is going?
让我重新运行valiate.py的python 然后输入
Let me rerun python of validate.py and type
在我一直在做的事情中 到目前为止 Malan@atherard.edu
in as I keep doing, malan@harvard.edu, which up until now
尽管我做了这么多改变 我还是继续工作
has kept working despite all of my changes.
但现在 呃 我终于破解了我自己的电子邮件地址
But now, ugh, finally I've broken my own email address.
那么 从逻辑上讲 这里的解决方案是什么？
So logically what's the solution here?
好吧 我们有很多办法可以解决这个问题
Well, there's a bunch of ways we could solve this.
我也许可以开始使用两个正则表达式
I could maybe start using two regular expressions
并支持以下形式的电子邮件地址：username@domain.tld
and support email addresses of the form username@domain.tld,
或用户名@subdomain.domain.tld 其中TLD只是
or username@subdomain.domain.tld, where TLD just
指顶级域名 如EDU
means Top Level Domain, like edu.
或者我可以修改这个 因为我会
Or I could maybe just modify this one, because I'd
不希望有两个正则表达式或一个两倍大的正则表达式
prefer not to have two regular expressions or one that's twice as big.
为什么我不指定re.earch这个模式的部分是可选的呢？
Why don't I just specify to re.search that part of this pattern is optional?
我们之前看到的那个符号是什么？
What was the symbol we saw earlier that allows
你想具体说明之前的事情在技术上是可选的吗？
you to specify that the thing before it is technically optional?
观众：异性恋吧？
AUDIENCE: The straight bar?
我们把直杆当做--
We were using the straight bar as an--
可选 则将参数设置为可选
optional, make the argument optional.
大卫·马兰：所以我们可以
DAVID MALAN: So we could.
我们可以使用竖线和一些圆括号
We could use a vertical bar and some parentheses
然后说 “要么这里有东西 要么什么都没有 ”
and say, "either there's something here or there's nothing."
我们可以在括号中这样做
We could do that in parentheses.
但我认为实际上还有一种更简单的方法
But I think there's actually an even easier way.
观众：事实上 这是一个问号
AUDIENCE: Actually, it's a question mark.
大卫·马兰：的确 这是个问号
DAVID MALAN: Indeed, question mark.
回想一下我们第一组符号的总结
Think back to this summary here of our first set of symbols,
因此我们不仅有点和*和+ 而且还有一个问号 其中
whereby we had not just dot and * and +, but also a question mark, which
字面意思是“零或一次重复”
means literally "zero or one repetitions," which
实际上意味着可选
effectively means optional.
它要么在那里 一个 要么不是 零
It's either there, one, or it's not, zero.
现在 我该如何将它翻译成这里的代码呢？
Now, how can I translate that to this code here?
好 让我继续 用括号将我的模式的这一部分括起来
Well, let me go ahead and surround this part of my pattern with parentheses,
这并不意味着我想在用户的输入中使用括号
which doesn't mean I want literally a parentheses in the user's input,
我只是想把这些角色组合在一起
I just want to group these characters together.
事实上 这一点现在仍然有效
And in fact, this now will still work.
我只是在子域的新部分周围添加了圆括号
I've only added parentheses around the new part for the subdomain.
让我运行valiate.py的python
Let me run python of validate.py.
让我运行maran@cs50.atherard.edu 回车
Let me run malan@cs50.harvard.edu, Enter.
这一点仍然有效
That's still valid.
但需要明确的是 如果我再次为maran@atherard.edu运行它 它仍然是
But to be clear, if I rerun it again for malan@harvard.edu, that is still
无效 但如果我进入这里 在括号后面说 这不是无效的
invalid, but not if I go in here and say, after the parentheses, which
现在是一个逻辑单元 它是一大组想法在一起
now is one logical unit, it's one big group of ideas together,
我在那里加了一个问号
I add a single question mark there.
现在 这将告诉re.earch 括号中的整个内容
This will now tell re.search that that whole thing in parentheses
要么只在那里一次 要么根本不在那里 零次
can either be there once or be there not at all, zero times.
那么 当我运行它时 这意味着什么？
So what does this translate into when I run it?
好的 让我继续使用maran@cs50重新运行它
Well, let me go ahead and rerun it with malan@cs50.harvard.edu
所以子域就在那里
so that the subdomain is there.
这和以前一样管用
That works as before.
让我清空屏幕 然后再运行一次 蟒蛇
Let me clear my screen and run it again, python
用Malan@atherard.edu创建的validate.py 它曾经很有效 但后来崩溃了
of validate.py with malan@harvard.edu, which used to work then broke.
我们现在又开业了吗？
Are we back in business now?
我们是
We are.
这现在又是有效的了
That's now valid again.
关于这种方法的问题 我们在哪里使用了
Questions now on this approach, where we've used
不仅是问号 还有括号？
not just the question mark but the parentheses as well?
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
你说过它可以重复0次或1次
You said it works for zero or one repetitions.
如果你有更多呢？
What if you have more?
大卫·马兰：如果你有更多呢？
DAVID MALAN: What if you have more?
没关系
That's OK.
这就是你可以做的*
That's where you could do *.
*为零或更多 这为您提供了世界上所有的灵活性
* is zero or more, which gives you all the flexibility in the world.
观众：是的
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
所以我只是在问--
So I was just asking that--
使用问号时 只允许重复一次
with question marks, there's only one repetition allowed.
大卫·马兰：这意味着零或一次重复
DAVID MALAN: It means zero or one repetition.
所以它要么不在那里 要么就在那里
So it's either not there or it is there.
这就是为什么现在这个模式 如果我回到我的代码 即使再一次
And so that's why this pattern now, if I go back to my code, even though again,
诚然 它看起来很神秘 让我突出显示@符号之后的所有内容
it admittedly looks cryptic, let me highlight everything after the @ sign
在$符号之前
and before the $ sign.
这现在代表了一个域名 如获得者.edu
This now represents a domain name, like harvard.edu,
或域名内的子域
or a subdomain within the domain name.
为什么？
Why?
好的 右边的这部分和往常一样
Well, this part to the right is the same as always.
反斜杠w+的意思类似于哈佛或耶鲁
Backslash w + means something like Harvard or Yale.
反斜杠.edu的字面意思是“.edu”
Backslash .edu means literally ".edu."
所以新的部分是这样的
So the new part is this.
在圆括号中 我现在有了另一组反斜杠w+反斜杠圆点
In parentheses, I have another set of backslash w + backslash dot now.
但这一切都在括号中
But it's all in parentheses.
在那之后我现在有一个问号
I'm now having a question mark right after that,
这意味着括号中的整个东西也可以在那里
which means that whole thing in parentheses either can be there,
或者它不可能在那里
or it can't be there.
这两个都是可以接受的
It's either of those that are acceptable.
因此 一个问号实际上使一些东西成为可选的
So a question mark effectively make something optional.
去掉括号是不正确的
It would not be correct to remove the parentheses,
因为这意味着什么？
because what would this mean?
如果我去掉括号 那就意味着
If I removed the parentheses, that would mean
只有这个点是可选的 这并不是我们想要表达的
that only this dot is optional, which isn't really what we want to express.
我想要子域名 如CS50和附加点
I want the subdomain, like cs50 and the additional dot
在那里或不在那里的东西
to be what's there or not there.
这里还有一个关于正则表达式的问题怎么样？
How about one other question on regexes here?
观众：我们可以用这个作为用户名吗？
AUDIENCE: Can we use this for the usernames?
大卫·马兰：当然
DAVID MALAN: Absolutely.
我们还有其他问题
We still have other problems.
我们目前还没有解决所有的问题
We're not solving all of the problems today just yet.
但绝对是这样
But absolutely.
目前 我们不允许您的用户名中有句点
Right now, we are not letting you have a period in your username.
再一次 你们中的一些人拥有Gmail账户或其他账户 你
And again, some of you with Gmail accounts or other accounts, you
可能不仅仅是下划线、数字和字母
probably have not just underscores, numbers, and letters.
你可能也会来月经
You might have periods, too.
嗯 我们可以解决这个问题 而不是在这里使用问号本身
Well, we could fix that, not using question mark here per se.
但现在我们有了这些括号 我能做的是
But now that we have these parentheses at our disposal, what I could do
是这个吗
is this.
我可以用圆括号将反斜杠w括起来
I could use parentheses to surround the backslash w
说“任何单词字符” 也就是说 就像字母一样
to say "any word character," which is the same thing, again, as a letter,
或数字 或下划线
or a number, or an underscore.
但我也可以用竖条或其他的东西
But I could also or in, using a vertical bar, something else,
就像一个字面点
like a literal dot.
现在 需要转义一个文字点 否则它
Now, a literal dot needs to be escaped, otherwise it
代表任何角色 这将是一种倒退 是一种倒退
represents any character, which would be a regression, a step back.
但现在请注意我做了什么
But now notice what I've done.
在括号中 我告诉re.earch前几个字符
In parentheses, I'm telling re.search that those first few characters
在您的电子邮件地址中 这是您的用户名
in your email address, that is your username,
必须是单词字符 如A到z、大写或小写或0
has to be a word character, like A through z, uppercase or lowercase, or 0
到9、下划线或直接点
through 9, or an underscore, or a literal dot.
我们也可以用不同的方式来做这件事
We could do this differently, too.
我可以去掉括号和
I could get rid of the parentheses and the
或者 我可以只使用一组字符
or, and I could just use a set of characters.
我可以再一次手动说a到z A到Z 0到9
I could, again, manually say a through z, A through Z, 0 through 9,
下划线 然后我可以做一个带反斜杠句点的直接点
underscore, and then I could do a literal dot with a backslash period.
现在技术上我甚至不需要大写字母
And now I technically don't even need the uppercase,
因为我已经告诉电脑忽略这个案子了
because I'm already telling the computer to ignore case.
我可以随便挑一个
I can just pick one or the other.
哪个更好 真的由你自己决定
Which one is better is really up to you.
您认为可读性更好的版本通常是更好的设计
Whichever one you think is more readable would generally be the better design.
好的
All right.
让我提议我及时倒回这篇文章
Let me propose that I rewind this in time
回到我们停下来的地方 也就是这里
to where we left off, which was here.
让我提议 确实有
And let me propose that there are, indeed,
此解决方案仍有局限性 不仅仅是用户名 也不仅仅是
still limitations of this solution, not just with the username, not just
使用域名
with the domain name.
我们还是有点太严格了
We're still being a little too restrictive.
那么 您是否希望看到正式的正则表达式
So would you like to see the official regular expression
至少现在的浏览器在你输入电子邮件地址的时候都在使用
that at least browsers use nowadays whenever you type in an email address
到Web表单 并且该Web表单、浏览器
to a web form, and the web form, the browser,
告诉你是或否 你的电子邮件地址在句法上是有效的？
tells you yes or no, your email address is syntactically valid?
准备好的?
Ready?
这就是--这甚至不是正式的正则表达式
Here is-- and this isn't even officially the right regular expression.
它是浏览器使用的简化版本 因为它
It's a simplified version that browsers use because it
抓住大多数错误 但不是全部
catches most mistakes but not all.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
这是有效电子邮件地址的正则表达式
This is the regular expression for a valid email address,
至少作为现在的浏览器来实现它们
at least as browsers nowadays implement them.
现在乍一看 这件事非常神秘
Now it's crazy cryptic at first glance.
但请注意--它包裹在许多行上 但它只是一种模式
But note-- and it's wrapping on to many lines, but it's just one pattern.
但只要注意一下现在熟悉的符号就知道了
But just notice the now-familiar symbols.
在最上面有^符号
There is the ^ symbol at the very top.
在最后有一个$符号
There is the $ sign at the very end.
这里有一个方括号 然后还有一些
There is a square bracket over here and then some
这些范围加上其他字符
of these ranges plus other characters.
事实证明 你通常不会在电子邮件地址中看到这些字符
Turns out you don't normally see these characters in email addresses.
看起来你是在用某人的用户名咒骂他们
It looks like you're swearing at someone in their username.
但他们是合法的角色
But they're valid characters.
它们是正式有效的
They're valid officially.
这并不意味着Gmail将允许你放置$符号和其他
That doesn't mean that Gmail is going to allow you to put $ signs and other
用户名中的标点符号
punctuation in your username.
但从官方角度来看 一些服务器可能会允许这样做
But officially, some servers might allow that.
因此 如果您真的想验证用户的电子邮件地址
So if you really want to validate a user's email address,
你实际上会想出或复制粘贴类似这样的东西
you would actually come up with or copy-paste something like this.
但老实说 这看起来很神秘
But honestly, this looks so cryptic.
如果你手动打字 你很可能会犯错误
And if you were to type it out manually, you are so likely to make a mistake.
这里有什么更好的解决方案呢？
What's the better solution here instead?
在过去的几周里 图书馆就是你的朋友
This is where, per past weeks, libraries are your friend.
当然 互联网上的其他人 一个程序员
Surely someone else on the internet, a programmer more
比你更有经验的人 甚至已经想出了代码
experienced than you, even, has come up with code
使用这个正则表达式 甚至可以正确验证电子邮件地址
that validates email addresses properly, using this regular expression or even
比那更复杂的东西
something more sophisticated than that.
因此 一般来说 如果手头的问题是验证
So generally, if the problem at hand is to validate
非常常规的输入--电子邮件地址
input that is pretty conventional-- an email address,
URL 其中有官方定义的东西
a URL, something where there's an official definition that's
独立于你自己--找一个你喜欢的图书馆
independent of you yourself-- find a popular library that you're
在您的代码中轻松使用并使用它来验证电子邮件地址
comfortable using and use it in your code to validate email addresses.
这不一定是你自己应该发明的轮子
This is not a wheel, necessarily, that you yourself should invent.
不过 我们已经使用电子邮件地址反复开始
We've used email addresses, though, to iteratively start
从简单、过于简单的东西开始 并在此基础上建立起来
from something simple, too simple, and build on top of that.
因此 您当然可以想象仍然使用正则表达式
So you could certainly imagine using regular expressions still
要验证不是电子邮件地址但却是
to validate things that aren't email addresses but are
对您很重要的数据
data that are important to you.
所以至少我们现在有了这些积木
So we at least now have these building blocks.
现在 除了正则表达式本身
Now, besides the regular expressions themselves,
原来 在PythonRe中还有其他函数
it turns out there's other functions in Python's re
正则表达式的库
library for regular expressions.
其中有这样一个函数 re.Match
Among them is this function here, re.match,
这实际上与re.earch非常相似
which is actually very similar to re.search,
除非您不必指定^符号
except you don't have to specify the ^ symbol
在您的正则表达式的最开始处 如果您愿意
at the very beginning of your regex if you want
从字符串的开头开始匹配
to match from the start of a string.
按设计重新匹配将自动开始匹配
re.match by design will automatically start matching
从琴弦的开头给你
from the start of the string for you.
在精神上相似的是re.fullMatch 它做同样的事情 但不仅仅是
Similar in spirit is re.fullmatch, which does the same thing but not only
匹配字符串的开头但字符串的结尾 因此
matches at the start of the string but the end of the string, so that you,
同样 也不需要同时输入^符号或$符号
too, don't need to type in the ^ symbol or the $ sign as well.
但现在让我们继续转换回一些实际的代码
But let's go ahead and transition back now to some actual code,
借此我们在精神上解决一个不同的问题
whereby we solve a different problem in spirit.
而不是仅仅验证用户的输入
Rather than just validate the user's input
并确保它看起来像我们想要的 让我们
and make sure it looks the way we want, let's just
假设用户不会完全按照我们的要求键入数据
assume that the users are not going to type in data exactly as we want,
因此 我们将不得不清理他们的投入
and so we're going to have to clean up their input.
当您使用Google Form或Office 365 Form时 这种情况经常发生
This happens so often when you're using like a Google Form, or Office 365 form,
或任何其他用于收集用户输入的内容
or anything else to collect user input.
无论您的表单问题是什么 您的用户
No matter what your form question says, your users
不一定要遵循这些方向
are not necessarily going to follow those directions.
他们可能会继续输入一些
They might go ahead and type in something that's a little
格式与您可能喜欢的不同
differently formatted than you might like.
现在 你当然可以浏览结果并下载CSV
Now, you could certainly go through the results and download a CSV,
或者打开Google电子表格 或类似的Excel
or open the Google spreadsheet, or equivalent in Excel,
然后手动清理所有数据
and just clean up all of the data manually.
但是如果你有很多的意见书--几十个
But if you've got lots of submissions-- dozens,
成百上千的数据行--
hundreds, thousands of rows in your data set--
手动操作可能不是很有趣
doing things manually might not be very fun.
写代码可能会更有效 比如Python
It might be much more effective to write code, as in Python,
这可以让您清理数据以及任何未来的数据
that can allow you to clean up that data and any future data as well.
所以我建议我们继续关闭validate.py
So let me propose that we go ahead here and close validate.py.
让我们继续创建一个新的程序 叫做format.py
And let's go ahead and create a new program altogether called format.py,
其目标是将用户的输入重新格式化为我们期望的格式
the goal of which is to reformat the user's input in the format we expect.
我将继续运行format.py代码
I'm going to go ahead and run code of format.py.
假设我们要重新格式化的数据
And let's suppose that the data we're going to reformat
是用户的名字--所以这次不是电子邮件地址而是名字
is the user's name-- so not email address but name this time.
我们希望他们输入自己的名字
And we're going to hope that they type in their name
像大卫·马兰一样
properly, like David Malan.
但有些用户可能已经习惯了
But some users might be in the habit, for whatever
如果你愿意的话 倒着打他们的名字
reason, of typing their name backwards, if you will,
用一个逗号 如马兰逗号大卫代替
with a comma, such as Malan comma David instead.
现在 这很好 因为两者对人类来说都是可读的
Now, it's fine because both are clearly as readable to the human.
但如果你想标准化这些名字的存储方式
But if you want to standardize how those names are stored
在您系统中 可能是数据库、CSV文件或其他文件
in your system, perhaps a database, or CSV file, or something else,
如果能至少标准化或规范化格式
it would be nice to at least standardize or canonicalize the format in which
你在存储你的数据 这样如果你打印出用户的名字
you're storing your data, so that if you print out the user's name
都是一样的格式 大卫·马兰
it's always the same format, David Malan,
没有逗号也没有落后
and there's no commas or backwardness to it.
让我们继续做一些熟悉的事情
So let's go ahead and do something familiar.
让我们给自己一个变量name
Let's go ahead and give myself a variable called name
并将其设置为等于input的返回值
and set it equal to the return value of input,
问用户 就像我们做过很多次的那样 “你叫什么名字 ”
asking the user, as we've done many times, "what's your name,"
问号
question mark.
我要继续前进 至少主动清理一些混乱
I'm going to go ahead and proactively at least clean up some messiness,
就像我们在这里一直做的那样 去掉所有的前导或尾随空格
as we keep doing here, by just stripping off any leading or trailing whitespace.
以防用户不小心按到空格键
Just in case the user accidentally hits the spacebar,
我们不希望最终在我们的数据集中出现这种情况
we don't want that ultimately in our data set.
现在让我继续 就像我们以前做过的那样
And now let me go ahead and do this as we've done before.
让我快速地继续并打印出来 只是为了确保
Let me just go ahead quickly and print out, just to make sure
我的开头是正确的 “你好 ”然后用花括号命名
I'm off to the right start, "hello," and then in curly braces name,
因此 创建一个fstring来格式化“Hello”、“Comma”、“name”
so making an fstring to format "hello," comma, "name."
现在 让我继续清理屏幕并运行格式为.py的python
Now let me go ahead and clear my screen and run python of format.py.
让我像往常一样输入我的名字 大卫 空格 马兰
Let me behave and type in my name as I normally would, David, space, Malan,
进来吧
Enter.
我认为产出看起来相当不错
And I think the output looks pretty good.
从语法上看 这与预期不谋而合
It looks as expected grammatically.
不过 现在让我继续 再玩一次这个游戏
Let me now go ahead, though, and play this game again.
但这一次 也许是因为我没在想
But this time, maybe because I'm not thinking,
或者我只是习惯了先用姓氏逗号
or I'm just in the habit of doing last name comma first,
我执行马兰、逗号、大卫 然后按回车键
I do Malan, comma, David, and hit Enter.
好的
All right.
好吧 现在这太奇怪了
Well, this now is weird.
即使程序只是吐出我输入的内容
Even though the program is just spitting out exactly what I typed in,
可以说 这并不接近正确 至少在语法上是这样
arguably this is not close to correct, at least grammatically.
它真的应该说“你好 大卫·马兰 ”
It should really say "hello, David Malan."
现在 也许我可以有一些如果条件
Now, maybe I could have some if conditions
如果用户输入逗号 我可以拒绝用户的输入
and I could just reject the user's input if they type a comma
或者以某种方式把他们的名字倒过来
or get their names backwards somehow.
但如果用户已经有了 那就太少了 太迟了
But that's going to be too little too late if the user has already
在网上提交了一份表格 我已经有了数据
submitted a form online, and I already have the data,
现在我要进去把它清理干净
and now I need to go in and clean it up.
而且手动检查也不会很有趣
And it's not going to be fun to go through manually
在Google电子表格、Apple Numbers或Microsoft Excel中
in Google Spreadsheets, or Apple Numbers, or Microsoft Excel
并手动修改许多人的名字以去掉逗号
and manually fix a lot of people's names to get rid of the commas
按照美国的惯例 把名字移到最后一个名字之前
and move the first name before the last, as is conventional in the US.
那就让我们开始吧
So let's do this.
它可能有点脆弱 但让我们开始
It could be a little fragile, but let's start
在这里以编程的方式来表达我们自己 并提出这个问题
to express ourselves a little programmatically here and ask this.
如果这个人的名字里有一个逗号 这是毕多德式的--
If there is a comma in the person's name, which is Pythonic--
我只是在问 这根更短的绳子是不是在这根更长的绳子上？
I'm just asking the question, is this shorter string in this longer string?--
那就让我继续做这件事
then let me go ahead and do this.
让我们继续在变量中获取该名称
Let me go ahead and grab that name in the variable,
不仅在逗号上拆分 还在后面的空格上拆分
split on not just the comma but the space after,
假设人类在他们的名字后面输入了一个空格
assuming the human typed in a space after their name.
让我继续存储拆分Malan、逗号、
And let me go ahead and store the result of that splitting of Malan, comma,
大卫分为两个变量
David into two variables.
让我们最后做一次 逗号 首先 再打开包装
Let's do last, comma, first, again unpacking
返回的值序列
the sequence of values that comes back.
现在让我继续并重新设置名称的格式
Now let me go ahead and reformat the name.
因此 我将强制将用户名更改为我所期望的名称
So I'm going to forcibly change the user's name to be as I expect.
因此名称实际上将是这样的格式字符串--
So name is actually going to be this format string--
先是名 然后是姓 两者都用大括号括起来 但格式在一起
first name then last name, both in curly braces but formatted together
只有一个空格 所以我会覆盖用户的输入
with a single space, so that I'm overwriting the user's input
并相应地更新我的名字变量
and updating my name variable accordingly.
目前 需要明确的是 这个项目是互动的
For the moment, to be clear, this program is interactive.
就像 用户 像我一样 在程序中输入他们的名字
Like, the users, like me, are typing their name into the program.
但是假设数据已经在CSV文件中
But imagine the data already is in a CSV file.
它来自某个过程 比如谷歌表格或其他在线工具
It came in from some process like a Google Form or something else online.
您可以想象编写类似于下面这样的代码
You could imagine writing code similar to this,
但它可能会先将该文件读入内存
but that maybe goes and reads that file into memory first.
也许它是通过CSV阅读器或DictReader的CSV
Maybe it's a CSV via CSV Reader or DictReader,
然后对每一个名字进行迭代
and then iterating over each of those names.
但我们会保持简单 一次只做一个名字
But we'll keep it simple and just do one name at a time.
但现在有趣的是 如果我回到我的终端窗口
But now what's kind of interesting here is if I go back to my terminal window
并将其清除 然后运行格式为.py的python
and clear it, and run python of format.py,
然后按Enter键 我将像以前一样输入David space Malan
and hit Enter, I'm going to type in David, space, Malan as before.
我觉得我们还是不错的
And I think we're still good.
但我也要继续这样做--
But I'm also going to go ahead and do this--
格式为.py Malan、逗号、David的巨蟒 中间有空格
python of format.py Malan, comma, David, with a space in between,
祈祷我的手指并按回车键 瞧
crossing my fingers and hit Enter, and voila.
现在 这一点已经得到解决
That now has been fixed.
可以肯定的是 这是一件非常简单的事情
Such a simple thing to be sure.
但清理用户输入是如此普遍的必要
But it is so commonly necessary to clean up users input.
在这里 我们至少看到了一种非常容易做到这一点的方法
Here we see at least one way to do so pretty easily.
现在 公平地说 这里有一些问题
Now, to be fair, there's some problems here.
事实上 有人能想象这样一种场景吗？在这种情况下
And in fact, can someone imagine a scenario in which this code really
不能修复用户的输入？
doesn't fix the user's input?
即使在我的代码中修复了这个问题 还会出什么问题？
What could still go wrong even with this fix in my code?
有什么想法吗？
Any thoughts?
观众：如果他们输入他们的名字逗号 然后[INAUDIBLE]..
AUDIENCE: If they typed in their name comma and then [INAUDIBLE]..
大卫·马兰：哦 还有一件事
DAVID MALAN: Oh, and then something else.
嗯
Yeah.
举个例子 让我试试这个
So let me try this, for instance.
让我继续运行一个程序
Let me go ahead and run a program.
我是我认识的唯一的大卫·马兰
And I am the only David Malan that I know.
但假设我是 比如说 像这样的初级学生
But suppose I were, let's say, junior like this.
而且 至少在英语中 有时在那里加一个逗号是很常见的
And it's common, in English at least, to sometimes put a comma there.
你不一定需要逗号 但我
You don't necessarily need the comma, but I'm
那些使用逗号的人中的一个
one of those people who uses a comma.
那现在真的 真的坏了
That's now really, really broken.
所以我打破了一些假设
So I've broken some assumption there.
因此 这在这里肯定会出问题
And so that could certainly go wrong here.
还有什么？
What else?
好吧 让我继续 再运行一次
Well, let me go ahead and run this again.
如果我用马兰 逗号 大卫 没有空格
And if I did Malan, comma, David, no space,
因为我有点草率 我没有
because I'm being a little sloppy, I'm not
注意 当你有很多用户时 就会发生这种情况
paying attention, which is going to happen when you have lots of users
最终 好吧 这件事现在真的坏了
ultimately, well, this really broke now.
注意 我有一个ValueError 这是一个实际的异常
Notice I have a ValueError, an actual exception.
为什么？
Why?
因为Split应该将字符串分割成两个字符串
Well, because split is supposed to be splitting the string into two strings
通过寻找逗号和空格
by looking for the comma and a space.
但如果没有逗号和空格 它就不能将其分成两部分
But if there is no comma and space, it can't split it into two things.
事实上 左边有两个变量
And the fact that I have two variables on the left,
但我只能拿回右边的一样东西
but I'm only getting back one thing on the right,
这意味着我不能像这样做这段代码
means that I can't do this code quite as this.
因此 可以肯定的是 它是脆弱的
So it's fragile to be sure.
但是 如果我们至少能改进它 那不是很好吗？
But wouldn't it be nice if we could at least improve it?
例如 我们现在知道一些正则表达式语法
For instance, we now know some regular expressions syntax.
如果我至少想让这个空间成为可选空间呢？
What if I at least wanted to make this space optional?
嗯 我可以使用我新发现的正则表达式语法
Well, I could use my newfound regular expression syntax
然后打个问号 问号的意思是零或一件事
and put a question mark, Question mark means zero or one of the things
往左走
to the left.
左边的是什么？
What's the thing to the left?
从字面上看 这是一个空间
It's literally a space.
如果只有一样东西 我甚至不需要括号
I don't even need parentheses if there's just one thing there.
所以这将是一个模式的开始 它说 我必须有一个逗号
So that would be the start of a pattern that says, I must have a comma,
然后我可能有一个空格 也可能没有空格 之后是零个空格或一个空格
and then I may or may not have a space, zero or one spaces thereafter.
不幸的是 内置到str变量中的Split版本
Unfortunately, the version of split that's built into the str variable,
如本例所示 不支持正则表达式
as in this case, doesn't support regular expressions.
如果我们想要我们的正则表达式 我们需要在这里使用该库
If we want our regular expressions, we need to go use that library here.
所以让我继续做这件事
So let me go ahead and do this.
让我进去 让这个代码保持原样 但要放在最上面
Let me go in and leave this code as is but go up to the top
现在 导入re以导入正则表达式的库
now and import re to import the library for regular expressions.
现在让我继续 开始改变我的方法
And now let me go ahead and start changing my approach here.
我要继续做这件事
I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我将使用名为re.earch的相同函数
I'm going to use the same function called re.search,
我要去寻找一种模式
and I'm going to search for a pattern that I
思考将是最后的 逗号 首先
think will be last, comma, first.
因此 让我使用我新发现的正则表达式语法
So let me use my newfound regular expression syntax
代表一种模式 如马兰、逗号、空格、大卫
and represent a pattern for something like Malan, comma, space, David.
我怎么能这样做呢？
How can I do this?
好吧 在我对re.earch的引用中 我会有一些东西--
Well, inside of my quotes for re.search, I'm going to have something--
所以点+--
so dot +--
抱歉的
sorry.
我要吃点东西 所以点+
I'm going to have something, so dot +.
然后我会有一个逗号
Then I'm going to have a comma.
然后我会有一个空间
Then I'm going to have a space.
然后我要点+的东西
Then I'm going to have something dot +.
现在 我将先发制人地改进一下这一点
Now I'm going to preemptively refine this a little bit.
我想让这整个模式开始匹配
I want this whole pattern to start matching
在用户输入的开始处
at the beginning of the user's input.
所以我现在要把^加起来
So I'm going to add the ^ right away.
我还希望用户输入的末尾也匹配 这样我就
And I want the end of the user's input to be matched as well, so that I'm
从字面上看 任何字符都需要一次或多次 然后是逗号 然后是空格
literally expecting any character one or more times, then a comma then a space,
然后是任何其他字符一次或多次
then any other character one or more times.
然后就是这样了
And then that is it.
我将像以前一样传递name变量
And I'm going to pass in the name variable as before.
现在 当我们在过去使用re.earch时
Now, when we've used re.search in the past,
我们真的只是用它来回答一个问题
we really used it just to answer a question.
用户的输入是否与以下模式匹配
Does the user's input match the following pattern or not,
对或错 有效地
true or false, effectively.
但re.search实际上比这更强大
But re.search is actually more powerful than that.
你实际上可以得到更多的信息
You can actually get back more information.
你可以做到这一点
And you can do this.
您可以指定一个变量 然后指定一个赋值运算符
You can specify a variable and then an assignment operator,
并在搜索时得到关于所发现内容的更准确的答案
and get back more precise answers to what has been found when searched for.
但你想要拿回什么呢？
But what is it you want to get back?
事实证明 正则表达式还有另一个特性
Well, it turns out there's this other feature of regular expressions
它允许你使用括号 而不仅仅是把东西组合在一起
which allow you to use parentheses, not just to group things together,
而是为了抓住他们
but to capture them.
结果是 当您在正则表达式中指定括号时
It turns out when you specify parentheses in a regular expression
到目前为止我们还不知道 括号里的一切
unbeknownst to us up until now, everything in the parentheses
将作为re.earch函数的返回值返回给您
will be returned to you as a return value from the re.search function.
它将允许你提取特定数量的信息
It's going to allow you to extract specific amounts of information
来自用户自己的输入
from the user's own input.
您也可以通过使用非捕获版本来逆转此过程
You can reverse this process, too, by using the non-capturing version
也是
as well.
你可以使用圆括号 然后是一个问号和一个冒号
You can use parentheses, and then literally a question mark, and a colon,
然后还有一些其他的东西
and then some other stuff.
也就是说 不要捕捉到这一点
And that will say, don't either capturing this.
我只是想把东西组合起来
I just want to group things.
但现在 我们将只使用括号本身
But for now, we're going to use just the parentheses themselves.
那么我该怎么做呢？
So how am I going to do this?
好吧 如果我想拿回用户的姓和名
Well, if I want to get back the user's last name and first name,
我想我要捕捉的是这里的点+和这里的点+
I think what I want to capture is the dot + here and the dot + here.
所以我特意用括号括起来
So I've deliberately surrounded in parentheses
逗号左右两边的点+
the dot + both to the left and the right of the comma,
不是因为我把它们归类在一起--
not because I'm grouping them together per se--
我没有加问号 我没有加另一个+或*--
I'm not adding a question mark, I'm not adding up another + or a *--
我现在使用圆括号来进行捕获
I'm using parentheses now for capturing purposes.
为什么？
Why?
好的 接下来我要做这个
Well, I'm going to do this next.
我仍然会问一个布尔问题 比如 “如果有匹配的话
I'm going to still ask a Boolean question like, "if there are matches,
那就这样做吧
then do this."
因此 如果匹配不是有效的假 就像没有匹配
So if matches is not effectively false, like none,
我希望我能拿回几根火柴
I do expect I've gotten back some matches.
看看我现在能做什么
And watch what I can do now.
我可以做最后一个 逗号 第一个等于
I can do last, comma, first equals whatever matches in
并取回所有的火柴组
and get back all of the groups of matches.
然后继续使用格式字符串更新名称 就像前面一样
Then go ahead and update name just like before with a format string
先做 然后用大括号做最后一次
and do first and then last in curly braces
同样 然后在最底部 就像以前一样 打印出来
as well, and then at the very bottom, just like before, print out,
例如 “你好”、“逗号”、“名字”
for instance, "hello," comma, "name."
因此 新代码现在是这里突出显示的所有内容
So the new code now is everything highlighted here.
我使用re.earch来搜索用户是否输入了他们的名字
I'm using re.search to search for whether the user typed their name
最后 逗号 第一种格式
in last, comma, first format.
但我更强大的是使用re.earch来捕获用户的一些输入
But I am more powerfully using re.search to capture some of the user's input.
什么会被抓获？
What's going to get captured?
我用括号括起来的任何东西都会
Anything I surrounded in parentheses will
作为返回值返回给我
be returned to me as return values.
如何获得这些返回值？
How do you get at those return values?
你问你为所有组赋值的变量
You ask the variable to which you assign them for all of the groups,
捕获的所有括号组
all of the groups of parentheses that were captured.
所以让我继续做这件事
So let me go ahead and do this.
现在让我继续运行格式为.py的python 回车
Let me go ahead now and run python of format.py, Enter.
我要像往常一样输入我的名字
And I'm going to type my name as usual.
在本例中 此If条件不会发生任何事情
In this case, nothing happens with this if condition.
为什么？
Why?
因为我没有键入逗号 所以此搜索没有找到逗号
Because I did not type a comma, and so this search does not find a comma,
所以没有火柴
so there are no matches.
所以我们立刻打印出“你好 名字”
So we immediately just print out "hello, name."
那里没有什么有趣或新鲜的东西
Nothing interesting or new there.
但如果我现在继续 并清除屏幕 并运行格式为.py的python
But if I now go ahead, and clear my screen, and run python of format.py,
然后做马兰语 逗号 空格 大卫 回车 我们重新格式化了我的名字
and do Malan, comma, space, David, Enter, we've reformatted my name.
好吧 这是怎么回事？
Well, how did this work?
现在让我说得更清楚一些
Let me be a little more explicit now.
事实证明 我不需要只说匹配 团体
It turns out I don't have to just say matches.groups.
我可以让我想要的特定群体回来
I can get specific groups back that I want.
所以让我稍微修改一下我的代码
So let me change my code a little bit more.
让我现在继续 只说这一点
Let me go ahead now and just say this.
让我们将名字更新为--
Let's update name to--
实际上 让我们开始吧
actually, let's do this.
假设最后一个名字将出现在比赛中
Let's say that the last name is going to be in the matches
但具体来说是第一组
but specifically group 1.
第一个名字将出现在比赛中 但特别是第二组
The first name is going to be in the matches but specifically group 2.
为什么是1和2？
Why 1 and 2?
因为这是逗号左边的第一组括号
Because this is the first set of parentheses to the left of the comma.
这是逗号右侧的第二组括号
This is the second set of parentheses to the right of the comma.
根据输入 这将是用户的姓氏
And based on the input, this would be the user's last name
在这种情况下 马兰
in this scenario, Malan.
在此场景中 这将是用户的名字David
This would be the user's first name, David, in this scenario.
这就是我使用组1作为姓氏的原因
That's why I'm using group 1 for the last name
名为组2
and group 2 for the first name.
现在我要继续说名字等于fstring 再一次 首先
And now I'm going to go ahead and say name equals fstring, again, first
然后 最后 完成
and then last, done.
在我们回答问题之前 让我来完善这最后一步
And let me refine this one last step before we take questions.
如果我立即使用这些变量 我实际上并不需要它们
I don't really need these variables if I'm immediately using them.
让我们继续前进 进一步加强这一点 就像我们已经
Let's just go ahead and tighten this up further as we've
过去是为了设计而做的
done in the past for design's sake.
如果我想要将该名称作为串联
If I want to make the name the concatenation
这个人的名字和姓氏
of the person's first name and last name,
我们就这么做吧 匹配 首先是第2组
let's just do this. matches.group 2 first,
加一个空格 加火柴 第一组
plus a space, plus matches.group 1.
所以从左到右由我决定 这是第一组
So it's just up to me from left to right, this is group 1,
这是第二组
this is group 2.
所以第一组是最后 第二组是第一
So group 1 is last, group 2 is first.
因此 如果我想反转它们并更新名称的值
So if I want to flip them around and update the value of name,
我可以首先显式地获取组2 使用+、单个空格
I can explicitly get group 2 first, concatenate using +, a single space,
然后在组1上串连
and then concatenate on group 1.
好的
All right.
那真是太多了
That was a lot.
让我暂停一下 看看是否有问题
Let me pause to see if there are questions.
这里的关键不同之处在于 我们仍然使用完全相同的re.search
The key difference here is we're still using re.search the exact same way,
但现在我使用它的返回值 而不仅仅是回答
but now I'm using its return value, not just to answer
一个问题是对还是错 但实际上
a question true or false, but to actually
找回我捕捉到的任何匹配的东西 可以这么说
get back specific matches anything I captured, so to speak,
加上圆括号
with parentheses.
观众：为什么我们用的是1和2而不是0和1
AUDIENCE: Why is it here we're using 1 and 2 instead of 0 and 1
因为抓到了第一个？
for capturing the first?
大卫·马兰：这个问题问得很好
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
观察得很好
A good observation.
在几乎所有其他背景下 我们已经开始
In almost every other context, we've started
数到0和1 而不是1和2
counting at 0 and 1 instead of 1 and 2.
原来在0号位置还有其他东西
It turns out there's something else in location 0
当它从re.earch返回时 它与字符串本身相关
when it comes back from re.search related to the string itself.
因此 仅根据此函数的文档
So according to the documentation of this function only,
1是第一组括号 2是第二组括号
1 is the first set of parentheses, and 2 is the second set,
从那以后
and onward from there.
只是这里有一个不同的会议
Just a different convention here.
还有其他问题吗？
Other questions?
观众：如果我们什么都不写呢 比如空格、逗号、空格？
AUDIENCE: What if we write nothing, like whitespace, comma, whitespace?
我们如何检查条件的真实性？
How do we check truth of condition?
David Malan：在我直接回答之前 让我
DAVID MALAN: Before I answer directly, let me just
运行这个 并确保我没有进一步打破任何东西
run this and make sure I've not broken anything further.
让我运行格式为.py的python
Let me run python of format.py.
让我以正确的方式输入大卫、空格、马兰
Let me type in David, space, Malan, the right way.
让我再运行一次
Let me run it once more.
让我输入Malan 逗号 David 这是我们正在修复的错误方式
Let me type in Malan, comma, David, the wrong way that we're fixing.
我们还是很棒的
And we're still good.
但我认为它还是会破裂的
But I think it will still break.
让我用马兰 逗号 大卫第三次运行它 没有空格
Let me run it a third time with Malan, comma, David with no space.
现在它还是坏了
And now it's still broken.
为什么？
Why?
因为我还在找逗号空格
Because I'm still looking for comma space.
现在 我怎么才能解决这个问题呢？
Now, how can I fix that?
我可以这样做的一种方法是在这里加一个问号 这又一次
One way I could do that is to add a question mark here, which again,
是零个或多个以前的东西
is zero or more of the thing before.
所以如果我有一个空格 然后是一个问号 不需要任何
So if I have a space and then a question mark literally, no need for any
括号 那么我完全可以容忍马兰语、逗号、空格、
parentheses, then I can literally tolerate both Malan, comma, space,
大卫或马兰 逗号 大卫
David or Malan, comma, David.
所以让我们再试一次
So let's try again.
以前 这是行不通的
Before, this did not work.
让我们做马兰 逗号 大卫 没有空格
Let's do Malan, comma, David with no space.
现在它确实起作用了
Now it does actually work.
所以我们可以容忍不同数量的空格
So we can tolerate different amounts of whitespace
如果我用我的公式更精确一点的话
if I am a little more precise with my formula.
让我继续 再试一次
Let me go ahead and try once more.
让我很奇怪 但可能会按空格键太多次
Let me very weirdly but possibly hit the space bar a few too many times
所以现在他们真的分开了
so now they're really separated.
这又一次不会有很好的效果 因为它
This, again, is not going to work quite right, because it's going
来消耗所有的空格
to consume all of that whitespace.
所以现在我可能想要脱光衣服 左右 任何
So now I might want to strip, left and right, any
结果上的前导空格 或者我能在这里做些什么
of the leading white space on the result. Or what I could do here
就是这么说
is say this.
我可以在这里使用* 所以空格* 而不是0或1
Instead of zero or one, I could use a * here, so space *.
现在如果我用马兰、逗号、空格再运行一次
And now if I run this once more with Malan, comma, space, space, space,
大卫 进来 现在我们已经把东西收拾得更干净了
David, Enter, now we've cleaned up things further.
所以你可以想象 取决于你的数据有多混乱
So you can imagine, depending on how messy the data is that you're
清理后 您的正则表达式可能需要
cleaning up, your regular expressions might need
变得越来越复杂
to get more and more sophisticated.
这真的取决于我们想一次解决多少问题
It really depends on just how many problems we want to solve at once.
好吧 请允许我提议我们继续前进 只是为了把这件事清理干净
Well, allow me to propose that we forge ahead further just to clean this up
更重要的是 使用一种实际上
even more so, using a feature that's actually
对Python本身来说是相对较新的
relatively new to Python itself.
这在使用正则表达式时非常常见
It is very common when using regular expressions
来做我在这里所做的事情--调用一个像re.earch这样的函数
to do exactly what I've done here-- to call a function like re.search
在里面捕获圆括号 这样您就可以返回一个
with capturing parentheses inside, such that you get back a return
我称之为匹配的价值--你可以叫它其他的东西
value that I'm calling matches-- you could call it something else,
但我默认将其称为匹配
but I'm calling it by default matches.
然后注意下一行 我说的是“如果匹配”
And then notice on the next line, I'm saying "if matches."
如果我能把事情做得更紧一些 做这些不是很好吗？
Wouldn't it be nice if I could just tighten things up further and do these
都在同一条线上？
all on the same line?
嗯 你可以这么说
Well, you can sort of.
让我继续做这件事
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我把这个If处理掉
Let me get rid of this if.
让我试着说这样的话
And let me just try to say something like this.
如果匹配等于re.earch 然后是冒号--
If matches equals re.search and then colon--
因此 将我的if条件合并到一行中 而不是这两行
so combining my if condition into just one line instead of those two.
在C、C++或Java中 您实际上会这样做
In C, or C++, or Java, you would actually do something like this,
把整件事用括号括起来
surrounding the whole thing with parentheses,
有时设置双倍以抑制任何警告
sometimes double sets to suppress any warnings,
如果你想同时做两件事
if you want to do two things at once.
如果您不仅希望将re.earch的返回值
If you want to not only assign the return value of re.search
设置为名为Matches的变量 但您希望
to a variable called matches, but you want
接下来要问一个布尔问题 这实际上是对的还是错的
to subsequently ask a Boolean question, is this effectively true or false.
这就是我刚才正在做的
That's what I was doing a moment ago.
让我来解开这一切
Let me undo this.
刚才 我正在取回返回值
A moment ago, I was getting back the return value
然后把它分配给火柴 然后我就问了这个问题
and assigning it to matches, and then I was asking the question.
好的 结果是这两行代码可能需要擦除
Well, it turns out this need to have two lines of code presumably rubbed
人们在Python中犯错误的时间太长了
people wrong for too long in Python.
所以你现在可以把这两种线结合成一条线
And so you can now combine these two kinds of lines into one.
但你需要一个新的接线员
But you need a new operator.
你不能只说 “如果匹配等于re.earch”
You cannot just say, "if matches equals re.search"
然后放在结尾处的冒号里
and then in a colon at the end.
相反 您需要这样做
You instead need to do this.
如果且仅当您想要赋值某项时 才需要执行冒号等于
You need to do colon equals if and only if you want to assign something
从右到左 你想问一个if或elif
from right to left and you want to ask an if or an elif
问题在同一条线上
question on the same line.
正如这里所看到的 这被亲切地称为海象操作员
This is affectionately known, as can see here, as the walrus operator.
而且这是近几年来对Python来说的新事物
And it's new to Python in recent years.
它既允许您像我从右到左所做的那样赋值
And it both allows you to assign a value as I'm doing from right to left,
问一个布尔式的问题 就像我
and ask a Boolean question about it, like I'm
用If或等效的Elif做什么
doing with the if or equivalently elif.
有人知道为什么这个叫海象操作员吗？
Does anyone know why this is called the walrus operator?
如果你这样看它 也许
If you kind of look at it like this, perhaps,
如果你熟悉海象 它看起来有点像海象
if you're familiar with walruses, it kind of sort of looks like a walrus.
因此 这是一个次要的细节 但相对较新的功能 说实话 您将
So a minor detail but a relatively new feature of Python that honestly, you'll
可能会继续在网上、源代码和教科书中看到
probably continue to see online, and in source code, and in textbooks,
以此类推 现在它确实存在了 越来越多地如此
and so forth, increasingly so now that it does exist.
这根本不会改变逻辑
It does not change the logic at all.
如果我运行格式为.py的python并输入Malan、逗号、空格、David
If I run python of format.py and type Malan, comma, space, David,
它仍然可以修复一些问题 但它只是稍微加强了我的代码
it still fixes things, but it's tightened up my code just a bit more.
好的
All right.
让我们继续看最后一个问题
Let's go ahead and look at one final problem
要解决的问题是 现在也要提取信息
to solve, that of extracting information now as well.
现在 我们已经验证了用户的输入
So at this point, we've now validated the user's input
通过检查它是否符合特定的模式
by checking whether or not it meets a certain pattern.
我们已经通过检查清理了用户的输入
We've cleaned up the user's input by checking
根据一个模式 无论它是否匹配 如果它
against a pattern, whether it matches or not, and if it
确实匹配 我们可以重新组织一些用户的信息
does match, we kind of reorganize some of the user's information
这样我们就可以清理他们的输入 并标准化我们
so we can clean up their input and standardize the format in which we're
在这种情况下 存储或打印它
storing or printing it, in this case.
让我们来做最后一个例子 其中我们非常明确地提取
Let's do one final example where we're very specifically extracting
信息 以回答一些问题
information in order to answer some question.
因此 让我提出这一点
So let me propose this.
让我们继续关闭Format.py并创建一个名为twitter.py的新文件
Let me go ahead and close format.py and create a new file called twitter.py,
它的目标是提示用户输入他们的Twitter个人资料的URL
the goal of which is to prompt users for the URL of their Twitter profile
并从中提取 从该URL推断出用户的用户名
and extract from it, infer from that URL, what is the user's username.
现在 你为什么要这么做呢？
Now, why might you want to do this?
首先 您可能希望用户能够非常轻松地复制和粘贴
Well, one, you might want users to be able to just very easily copy and paste
从他们自己的Twitter个人资料到您的表单、到您的应用程序的URL
the URL from their own Twitter profile into your form, into your app,
这样你就可以知道他们的用户名是什么
so that you can figure out what their username is.
或者你可能有一个表单 要求用户输入他们的Twitter用户名
Or you might have a form that asks the user for their Twitter username,
因为人们不一定会非常密切地关注
and because people aren't necessarily paying very close attention,
有些人会输入他们的用户名
some people type their username.
有些人会打出他们的整个URL或其他东西
Some people type their whole URL or something else altogether.
现在你是一名程序员 那就太好了
It would be nice now that you're a programmer
只是更能容忍不同类型的输入
to just be more tolerant of different types of input
承担起规范化、标准化数据的重担
and just take on the burden of canonicalizing, standardizing the data,
而是灵活地对待用户
but being flexible with the users.
如果你只是让我复制粘贴 它可以说是更好的用户体验
It's arguably a better user experience if you just let me copy-paste
或者输入我想要的东西 你就把它清理干净
or type in what I want, you clean it up.
你是程序员 不是我
You're the programmer not me.
可能会带来更好的体验
Lends for a better experience, perhaps.
那么 让我继续使用twitter.py来做这件事
Well, let me go ahead and do this with twitter.py.
让我首先在这里提示用户输入变量的值
Let me first go ahead and prompt the user here for a value for a variable
我会调用url 让他们输入他们Twitter个人资料的URL
that I'll call url, and just ask them to input the URL of their Twitter profile.
我要脱掉所有的主角
I'm going to go ahead and strip off any leading
或尾随空格 以防用户不小心按下空格键
or trailing whitespace, just in case users accidentally hit the spacebar.
从字面上说 这是我能很容易做到的最低限度
That's literally the least I can do quite easily.
但现在让我们继续做这件事
But now let's go ahead and do this.
假设用户的地址如下
Suppose that the user's address is the following.
让我把他们输入的内容打印出来
Let me print out what did they type in.
让我清空屏幕并运行twitter.py的python
And let me clear my screen and run python of twitter.py.
例如 我将继续输入
I'm going to go ahead and type in, for instance,
Https://twitter.com/davidjmalan  恰好是我自己的推特用户名
https://twitter.com/davidjmalan, which happens to be my own Twitter username.
现在 我们只需将其打印回屏幕
For now, we're just going to print it back onto the screen just
以确保我还没有搞砸
to make sure I've not messed up yet.
好的
OK.
所以我打印回了完全相同的URL
So I've printed back out the exact same URL.
但手头的目标是只提取用户名
But the goal at hand is to extract the username only.
现在 让我问一个直截了当的问题
Now, let me just ask, perhaps, a straightforward question.
从逻辑上讲 我需要做什么才能获得用户的用户名？
Logically, what do I need to do to get at the user's username?
观众：嗯 我们只是忽略用户名之前的内容
AUDIENCE: Well, we just ignore what's before the username
然后直接提取用户名？
and then just extract the username?
大卫·马兰：太好了
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
是的 我是说 就这么简单
Yeah, I mean, it is as simple as that.
如果您知道用户名在末尾 那么让我们
If you know the username is at the end, well, let's just
不知何故 从一开始就忽略了一切
somehow ignore everything to the beginning.
那么 开头是什么？
Well, what's at the beginning?
嗯 这是个网址
Well, it's a URL.
所以我们可能需要忽略HTTPS a：// twitter.com
So we're probably going to need to ignore an HTTPS, a ://, a twitter.com,
和a/
and a /.
所以我们只想把这一切都扔掉
So we just want to throw all of that away.
为什么？
Why?
因为如果它是一个URL 我们可以通过Twitter的工作原理来了解
Because if it's an URL, we know by how Twitter works
用户名位于末尾
that the username comes at the end.
因此 让我们使用这个非常简单的想法来获取我们想要的信息
So let's use that very simple idea to get at the information we want.
我将尝试几种不同的方法
I'm going to try this a few different ways.
让我在这里回到我的程序
Let me go back into my program here.
而不是仅仅打印出来 这只是为了看看发生了什么
And instead of just printing it out, which was just to see what's going on,
让我来做吧
let me do this.
让我创建一个名为UserName的新变量
Let me create a new variable called username.
让我打电话给url.place
And let me call url.replace.
结果是 如果URL是一个字符串或在Python中是一个字符串
It turns out that if URL is a string or a str in Python,
它又一次提供了多种方法 如剥离和分割
it, again, comes with multiple methods, like strip, and split,
还有其他的 其中一个被称为Replace
and others as well, one of which is called replace.
而Replace将会做到这一点
And replace will do just that.
您向它传递两个参数 第一个参数是 您想要替换什么？
You pass it two arguments, the first of which is, what do you want to replace?
第二个论点是 你想用什么来取代它？
The second argument is, what do you want to replace it with?
所以如果我想摆脱 就像我提议的那样
So if I want to get rid of, as I've proposed,
实际上就是用户名之前的所有内容
really just everything before the username,
也就是说 Twitter URL或其开头 让我们这样说吧
that is, the Twitter URL or the beginning thereof, let's just say this.
继续并替换“https://twitter.com/” “
Go ahead and replace "https://twitter.com/",
结束引用 这就是我想要取代的
close quote, that's what I want to replace.
逗号 第二个参数 你想用什么来代替它？
And comma, second argument, what do you want to replace it with?
没什么
Nothing.
所以我真的要用双引号引用
So I'm literally going to pass in quote unquote
以有效地进行查找和替换
to effectively do a find and replace.
这就是Replace方法所做的 就像您可以做的那样
That's what the replace method does, just like you can do it
在Microsoft Word或Google Docs中
in Microsoft Word or Google Docs.
这是程序员执行查找和替换的方式
This is the programmer's way of doing find and replace.
现在 让我继续并打印出用户名
Now let me go ahead and print out just the username.
因此 我将使用这样的fstring
So I'll use an fstring like this.
我会说用户名、冒号 然后用大括号括起来
I'll say username, colon, and then in curly braces,
用户名 只是为了更好地格式化它
username, just to format it nicely.
好的
All right.
让我继续清理我的屏幕并运行twitter.py Enter URL的python
Let me go ahead and clear my screen and run python of twitter.py, Enter, URL.
我们开始吧 Https://twitter.com/davidjmalan Enter
Here we go. https://twitter.com/davidjmalan, Enter.
好的
OK.
现在我们已经取得了一些进展
Now we've made some progress.
今天结束了 对吧？
Done for the day, right?
那么 这有什么不是最优的呢？
Well, what is suboptimal about this?
有人可以批评我的程序或对我的程序吹毛求疵吗？
Can anyone critique or find fault with my program?
它现在起作用了 但它有点脆弱
It is working now, but it's a little fragile.
我敢打赌 我们可以设计一些我认为它有效但它不起作用的场景
I bet we could contrive some scenarios where I think it works but it doesn't.
观众：事实上 我有几个想法
AUDIENCE: Well, I have a few ideas, actually.
那么 首先 如果我们不指定HTTPS 它就会被破坏
Well, first of all, if we don't specify HTTPS, it will be broken.
其次 如果我们在最后有一个斜杠 它也会被打破
Secondly, if we have a slash at the end, it also will be broken.
如果我们在问号之后有一个问号或别的什么
If we have a question mark or something after question mark,
它也不会起作用
it also won't work.
所以实际上有很多场景
So a lot of scenarios, actually.
大卫·马兰：哦 我的天
DAVID MALAN: Oh, my god.
我是说 我们来了
I mean, here we are.
我假装以为我完蛋了
I was pretending to think I was done.
但天哪 亚历克斯给了我们一大堆问题
But my god, like, Alex gave us a whole laundry list of problems.
简单地说 如果它不是HTTPS 而是HTTP呢？
And just to recap, then, what if it's not HTTPS, it's HTTP?
稍微不那么安全 但我还是应该
Slightly less secure, but I should still be
能够以编程方式容忍这一点
able to tolerate that programmatically.
如果协议不在那里怎么办？
What if the protocol is not there?
如果用户只需输入twitter.com/davidjmaran怎么办？
What if the user just typed twitter.com/davidjmalan?
如果能容忍这一点而不是表现出错误 那就好了
It would be nice to tolerate that rather than show an error
让我输入协议
and make me type in the protocol.
为什么？
Why?
它的用户体验并不好
It's not good user experience.
如果它在用户名的末尾有一个斜杠或一个问号怎么办？
What if it had a slash at the end of the username, or a question mark?
如果你想一想你在网上看到的URL
If you think about URLs you've seen on the web,
通常会有更多的信息 特别是
there's very commonly more information, especially
如果它被分享在社交媒体上
if it's been shared on social media.
可能有一个HTTP参数 可以这么说
There might be a HTTP parameters, so to speak,
只是我们不想要的东西
just stuff there that we don't want.
可能会有一个www.twitter.com 我也没有预料到 但确实是这样
There could be a www.twitter.com, which I'm also not expecting but does
如果您也转到该URL 就可以了
work if you go to that URL, too.
因此 有太多事情可能会出错
So there's just so many things that can go wrong.
即使我回到前面那个假想的例子
And even if I come back to my contrived example as earlier,
如果我运行这个程序 然后说--
what if I run this program and say this--
“我的用户名是https://twitter.com/davidjmalan ”
"my username is https://twitter.com/davidjmalan,"
进来吧
Enter.
嗯 这也不是真的起作用--它消除了--实际上--
Well, that too just didn't really work-- it got rid of the-- actually--
[笑]好的 实际上这种方法奏效了
[LAUGHS] OK, actually that kind of worked.
但这里的目标是实际获取用户的用户名
But the goal here is to actually get the user's username,
不是描述用户用户名的英文句子
not an English sentence describing the user's username.
所以我会争辩说 即使我只是意外地创造了
So I would argue that even though I just accidentally created
完全正确的英语语法 我没有
perfectly correct English grammar, I did not
正确提取Twitter用户名
extract the Twitter username correctly.
我不希望像“我的用户名是”这样的词作为我输入的一部分
I don't want words like "my username is" as part of my input.
那么 我们如何着手改善这一点 或许还能逐步减少
So how can we go about improving this, and maybe chipping away
在这些问题中一个接一个地解决？
at some of those problems one by one?
好吧 让我把我的屏幕清理一下
Well, let me clear my screen here.
让我回到我的准则上来
Let me come back up to my code.
让我不只是替换它 而是让我做一些其他的事情
And let me not just replace it, but let me do something else instead.
我将继续 而不是使用替换
I'm going to go ahead, and instead of using replace,
我将使用另一个名为emovePrefix的函数
I'm going to use another function called removeprefix.
前缀是一个字符串或子字符串 位于另一个字符串的开头
A prefix is a string or a substring that comes at the start of another.
所以如果我删除前缀 这个函数就不需要第二个参数了
So if I remove prefix, I don't need a second argument for this function.
我只需要一个
I just need one.
您要删除什么前缀？
What prefix do you want to remove?
所以这至少现在可以解决这个问题了
So this will at least now fix the problem I just
描述了像输入一个完整的句子一样 URL在那里
described of typing in like a whole sentence, where the URL is there,
但这并不是在开始 只是在结束
but it's not at the beginning, it's only at the end.
所以在这里 这仍然是不正确的
So here, this still is not correct.
但是我们不会创建这个看起来很奇怪的输出 只删除URL部分
But we don't create this weird-looking output that just removes the URL part
输入的--
of the input--
“我的用户名是https://twitter.com/davidjmalan.”
"my username is https://twitter.com/davidjmalan."
不久前 它确实删除了URL 只留下了davidjmaran
A moment ago, it did remove the URL and left only the davidjmalan.
这仍然不是完美的
This is not perfect still.
但至少现在 它没有奇怪地删除URL
But at least now, it does not weirdly remove the URL
然后离开英国人
and then leave the English.
它只是让它自生自灭
It's just leaving it alone.
所以也许我能更好地处理这件事 但至少
So maybe I could handle this better, but at least
它把它从我可能预料到的那部分绳子上去掉了
it's removing it from the part of the string I might anticipate.
那我们在这里还能做什么呢？
Well, what else could we do here?
事实证明 正则表达式只是
Well, it turns out that regular expressions just
让我们更准确地表达模式
let us express patterns much more precisely.
我们可以花一整天的时间使用一大堆不同的Python函数
We could spend all day using a whole bunch of different Python functions
比如RemvePrefix 或Remove and strial 以及其他 还有一些
like removeprefix, or remove, and strip, and others, and kind of
让我们找到正确的解决方案
make our way to the right solution.
但正则表达式只是允许您更简洁地
But a regular expression just allows you to more succinctly,
诚然 更隐晦地表达这些模式和目标
if admittedly more cryptically, express these kinds of patterns and goals.
我们已经从括号中看到 它可以
And we've seen from parentheses, which can
不仅用于将符号组合在一起作为集合
be used not just to group symbols together as sets
但为了捕捉信息 我们现在有一个非常强大的工具
but to capture information as well, we have a very powerful tool now
在我们的工具包里
in our toolkit.
那就让我来做吧
So let me do this.
让我继续在这里重新开始 并导入Re库
Let me go ahead and start fresh here and import the re library
就像以前一样 在我节目的顶端
as before at the very top of my program.
我仍然将通过相同的代码行获取用户的URL
I'm still going to get the user's URL via the same line of code.
但我现在还将使用另一个函数
But I'm now going to use another function as well.
事实证明 不只是re.earch或re.Match
It turns out that there's not just re.search, or re.match,
或者重新进行完全匹配
or re.fullmatch.
正则表达式库中也有re.sub. 这里的“sub.”
There's also re.sub in the regular expression library, where "sub" here
意思是“替身”
means "substitute."
这需要更多的论点 但它们相当直截了当
And it takes more arguments, but they're fairly straightforward.
Re.Sub的第一个参数是模式 即正则表达式
The first argument to re.sub is the pattern, the regular expression
你想要找的东西
that you want to look for.
然后你有一个替换的字符串--你要做什么
Then you have a replacement string-- what do
你想把那个图案换成吗？
you want to replace that pattern with?
你想在哪里做这一切？
And where do you want to do all that?
好的 您传入要对其进行替换的字符串
Well, you pass in the string that you want to do the substitution on.
然后还有一些其他的论点 我现在会对此挥手致意
Then there's some other arguments that I'll wave my hands at for now.
其中有同样的旗帜和一位伯爵
Among them are those same flags and also a count,
比如 你想做多少次查找和替换？
like how many times do you want to do find and replace?
你想让它做所有的事吗？你想只做一件吗
Do you want it to do all, do you want to do just one,
诸如此类 你也可以在那里有更多的控制权
or so forth you can have further control there, too,
就像你在谷歌文档或Microsoft Word中所做的那样
just like you would in Google Docs or Microsoft Word.
好吧 让我回到我的代码 让我来做这件事
Well, let me go back to my code here, and let me do this.
我将继续下去 不是搜索 而是re.sub.替换
I'm going to go ahead and call re not search but re.sub for substitute.
我将传递以下正则表达式
I'm going to pass in the following regular expression,
Https://twitter.com/“ 然后我将结束我的引述
"https://twitter.com/" and then I'm going to close my quote.
现在我想用什么来取代它呢？
And now what do I want to replace that with?
嗯 就像前面使用简单的字符串替换函数一样
Well, like before with the simple str replace function,
我想用什么都不用来取代它 只是干脆把它去掉
I want to replace it with nothing, just get rid of it altogether.
但我想传入什么字符串才能完成此操作呢？
But what string do I want to pass in to do this to?
来自用户的URL
The URL from the user.
现在 让我继续赋值reo的返回值
And now let me go ahead and assign the return value of re.sub
设置为一个名为UserName的变量
to a variable called username.
因此 Resub.的人生目标 再一次 是用
So re.sub's purpose in life is, again, to substitute
某个正则表达式的一些值的一些次数
some value for some regular expression some number of times.
它本质上是使用正则表达式查找和替换
It essentially is find and replace using regular expressions.
并将结果字符串返回给您
And it returns to you the resulting string
一旦你完成了所有这些替换
once you've done all those substitutions.
所以现在我的代码的最后一行可以和以前一样 打印--
So now the very last line of my code can be the same as before, print--
我将使用fstring、用户名、冒号 然后用大括号括起来
and I'll use an fstring, username, colon, and then in curly braces,
用户名
username.
这样我就可以打印出来了
So I can print out literally just that.
好的
All right.
让我们试一试 看看会发生什么
Let's try this and see what happens.
我将清除我的终端窗口 运行twitter.py的python
I'll clear my terminal window, run python of twitter.py.
我们来了 https://twitter.com/davidjmalan.
And here we go, https://twitter.com/davidjmalan.
祈祷我的手指 然后按回车键
Cross my fingers and hit Enter.
好了 现在我们开业了
OK, now we're in business.
但它仍然有点脆弱
But it is still a little fragile.
所以让我问问大家 我现在应该有什么问题
And so let me ask the group, what problem should I now
更进一步的打击？
further chip away at?
以前也有人这么说过 但让我们明确一点
They've been said before, but let's be clear.
还有什么一个或多个问题仍然存在？
What's one or more problems that still remain?
观众：协议和域名前缀[INAUDIBLE]..
AUDIENCE: The protocols and the domain prefix [INAUDIBLE]..
大卫·马兰：很好
DAVID MALAN: Good.
协议 所以HTTP与HTTPS
The protocols, so HTTP versus HTTPS.
也许子域名 www 它应该在那里还是不在那里？
Maybe the subdomain, www, should it be there or not?
这里还有其他几个错误
And there's a few other mistakes here, too.
让我真的留在这个团体里
Let me actually stay with the group.
目前的解决方案还有哪些其他缺点？
What are some other shortcomings of this current solution?
听众：如果我们像你以前那样使用一句话
AUDIENCE: If we use a phrase like you do before,
我们将面临同样的问题 因为它没有考虑到
we are going to have the same problem, because it's not taking account
在文本示例的第一部分中
in the first part of the text example.
大卫·马兰：很好
DAVID MALAN: Good.
我可能仍然允许URL左边的一些单词 一些英语
I might still allow for some words, some English to the left of the URL
因为我没有用我的^符号
because I didn't use my ^ symbol.
所以我会解决这个问题的
So I'll fix that.
对这里的不足之处有什么最后的看法吗？
And any final observations on shortcomings here?
观众：嗯 它可能是一个HTTP 也可能有不到两个斜杠
AUDIENCE: Well, it could be an HTTP, or there could be less than two slashes.
大卫·马兰：好的
DAVID MALAN: OK.
所以它可能是HTTP
So it could be HTTP.
我认为在礼仪方面也提到了这一点
And I think that was mentioned, too, in terms of protocol.
削减幅度可能不到两次
There could be fewer than two slashes.
我不会担心的
That I'm not going to worry about.
如果用户给了我 而不是两个 那就是用户的错误
If the user gives me instead of two, that's really user error.
我可以容忍 但你知道吗 在这一点上
And I could be tolerant of it, but you know what, at that point
我可以用一条错误消息对他们大喊大叫 说：请修改您的输入
I'm OK yelling at them with an error message saying, please fix your input.
否则 我们可能会整天呆在这里 试图处理所有可能的打字错误
Otherwise, we could be here all day long trying to handle all possible typos.
目前 我认为从可用性的角度来看
For now, I think in the interests of usability,
或用户体验 UX 至少让我们
or user experience, UX, let's at least be
容忍所有可能的有效输入或合理输入(如果您愿意)
tolerant of all possible valid inputs or reasonable INPUTS if you will.
所以让我说到这里 让我开始在这里慢慢地分析这些东西
So let me go here, and let me start chipping away at these here.
我们可以解决哪些问题？
What are some problems we can solve?
好吧 让我提议我们首先解决匹配的问题
Well, let me propose that we first address the issue of matching
从字符串的开头开始
from the beginning of the string.
所以让我在开头加上^
So let me add the ^ to the beginning.
不过 让我在结尾处不加$符号 对吗？
And let me add not a $ sign at the end, though, right?
因为我不想一直匹配到最后
Because I don't want to match all the way to the end,
因为我想容忍那里的用户名
because I want to tolerate a username there.
所以我想我们只需要那里有^符号
So I think we just want the ^ symbol there.
有一个微妙的漏洞 但还没有人提到
There's a subtle bug that no one yet mentioned.
让我来强调一下 看看你现在会不会想到它
And let me just kind of highlight it and see if it jumps out at you now.
在我的屏幕上有一点微妙
It's a little subtle here on my screen.
我在这里用蓝色突出显示了最后一个错误--
I've highlighted in blue a final bug here--
也许屏幕上会有一些微笑 对吧？
maybe some smiles on the screen, yeah?
我们能在这里牵一只手吗？
Can we take one hand here?
为什么我要在twitter.com上突出显示这个点 尽管它肯定是
Why am I highlighting the dot in twitter.com, even though it definitely
应该在那里吗？
should be there?
观众：不带反斜杠的圆点表示除换行符以外的任何字符
AUDIENCE: So the dot without a backslash means any character except a newline.
大卫·马兰：是的 确实如此
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
它指的是任何角色
It means any character.
所以我可以输入类似推特的东西 或者推特上的任何东西
So I could type in something like twitter?com, or twitter anything com,
而这实际上是可以容忍的
and that would actually be tolerated.
这并不是很糟糕 因为用户为什么要这样做？
It's not really that bad, because why would the user do that?
但如果我想要正确 我想要正确
But if I want to be correct, and I want to be
能够正确地测试我自己的代码 我真的应该正确地完成这个细节
able to test my own code properly, I should really get this detail right.
所以这也是一个很容易解决的问题 但这是一个常见的错误
So that's an easy fix, too, but it's a common mistake.
任何时候 当您编写的正则表达式恰好涉及
Anytime you're writing regular expressions that happen to involve
特殊符号 如URL或域名中的圆点
special symbols, like dots in a URL or domain name,
在涉及货币的东西中有一个$符号 记住你可能 确实
a $ sign in something involving currency, remember you might, indeed,
需要用这里这样的反斜杠来转义
need to escape it with a backslash like this here.
好的
All right.
让我具体问一下小组关于协议的问题
Let me ask the group about the protocol specifically.
因此 HTTPS在世界上是一件好事
So HTTPS is a good thing in the world.
意思是安全
It means secure.
正在使用加密
There is encryption being used.
因此 一般而言 您喜欢看到HTTPS
So generally, you like to see HTTPS.
但你仍然可以看到人们打字或复制粘贴HTTP
But you still see people typing or copy-pasting HTTP.
最简单的解决办法是什么 就像已经提出的那样
What would be the simplest fix here to tolerate, as has been proposed,
是否同时使用HTTP和HTTPS？
both HTTP and HTTPS?
我要提议我能做到这一点
I'm going to propose that I could do this.
我可以使用HTTP垂直条形图或HTTPS 也就是A或B
I could do HTTP vertical bar or HTTPS, which, again, means A or B.
但我想我可以比这更聪明
But I think I can be smarter than that.
我可以让我的代码更简洁一些
I can keep my code a little more succinct.
这里有什么关于容忍HTTP或HTTPS的建议吗？
Any recommendations here for tolerating HTTP or HTTPS?
观众：我们可以试着在S后面加个问号
AUDIENCE: We could try to put in question mark behind the S.
大卫·马兰：太好了
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
只需使用问号即可
Just use a question mark.
这两个都是可行的解决方案
Both of those would be viable solutions.
如果你想在你的代码中表现得非常明确 那没问题
If you want to be super explicit in your code, fine.
使用括号 并使用HTTP或HTTPS 这样您 读者 您的老板
Use parentheses and say HTTP or HTTPS, so that you, the reader, your boss,
你的老师完全知道你在做什么
your teacher just know exactly what you're doing.
但如果你一直采取更冗长的方法
But if you keep taking the more verbose approach all the time,
当然 它实际上可能会变得不那么可读性
it might actually become less readable, certainly
一旦您的正则表达式变得这么大 而不是这么大
once your regular expressions get this big instead of this big.
所以 让我们尽我们所能节省空间
So let's save space where we can.
我认为这是非常合理的 所以
And I would argue that this is pretty reasonable, so
只要您有阅读正则表达式的习惯
long as you're in the habit of reading regular expressions
并知道问号并不意味着字面上的问号
and know that question mark does not mean a literal question mark,
但它的意思是零或之前的一件事
but it means zero or one of the thing before.
我认为我们实际上已经将S设置为可选的
I think we've effectively made the S optional here.
现在 我还能做什么？
Now, what else can I do?
好吧 假设我们想要容忍WWW点 它可能存在也可能不存在
Well, suppose we want to tolerate the www dot, which may or may not be there,
但如果你打开浏览器 它就会起作用
but it will work if you go to a browser.
我可以做到这一点
I could do this--
WWW点--等等 我想要一个反斜杠 这样我就不会
www dot-- wait, I want a backslash there so I don't
重复和以前一样的错误
repeat the same mistake as before.
但这也不好 因为我想忍受在那里或不在
But this is no good either, because I want to tolerate being there or not
在那里
being there.
现在我只是要求它在那里
And now I've just required that it be there.
但我认为我可以采取同样的方法
But I think I can take the same approach.
有什么建议吗？
Any recommendations?
我怎么做才能让WWW
How do I make the www.
可有可无 就为了敲打这个家？
optional, just to hammer this home?
观众：我们可以分组--
AUDIENCE: We can group--
画一个正方形和一个问号
make a square and a question mark.
大卫·马兰：太好了
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
因此 问号又是一个简短的答案
So question mark is the short answer again.
但这一次我们必须更聪明一点
But we have to be a little smarter this time.
正如玛丽亚所指出的 我们现在需要括号
As Maria has noted, we need parentheses now.
因为如果我在圆点后面加一个问号
Because if I just put a question mark after the dot,
这只意味着点是可选的
that just means the dot is optional.
这是错误的 因为我们不希望用户输入
And that's wrong, because we don't want the user to type
在W-T-W-I-T-T-E-R 我们希望圆点在那里 或者根本不存在
in W-W-W-T-W-I-T-T-E-R. We want the dot to be there or just not at all with no
www.w.
www.
所以我们需要把这整件事归类在一起
So we need to group this whole thing together,
在那里放一个括号 然后放一个括号 而不是在第三个W之后
put a parenthesis there, and then a parenthesis, not after the third W,
在点之后 所以整个东西要么在那里 要么不在那里
after the dot, so that that whole thing is either there or it's not there.
我们还能在这里做些什么呢？
And what else could we still do here?
还有一件事是我们应该容忍的
There's going to be one other thing we should tolerate.
以前已经说过了 我会把这一条摘掉
And it's been said before, and I'll pluck this one off.
协议是怎么回事？
What about the protocol?
例如 如果用户只是不键入或不复制粘贴http：//
Like, what if the user just doesn't type or doesn't copy-paste the http://
或https://？
or an https://?
老实说 你和我都没有这个习惯
Honestly, you and I are not in the habit,
总体而言 现在甚至不再打字了
generally, of even typing the protocol anymore nowadays.
你只要让浏览器帮你找出来
You just let the browser figure it out for you,
并自动添加它
and automatically add it instead.
所以这张看起来更像一张嘴
So this one's going to look like more of a mouthful.
但如果我想让蓝色的这整件事是可选的
But if I want this whole thing here in blue to be optional,
这实际上与玛丽亚刚才提出的解决方案相同
it's actually the same solution as Maria offered a moment ago.
接下来我要在这里加上一个括号
I'm going to go ahead and put a parenthesis over here,
在两个斜杠后面加上一个括号 然后是一个问题
and a parenthesis after the two slashes, and then a question
标记 以使整个操作也成为可选的
mark so as to make that whole thing optional as well.
这样就可以了
And this is OK.
把这整件事做成这件事完全没问题
It's totally fine to make this whole thing
可选的 或者说里面 这个小东西 就是S的可选的
optional, or inside of it, this little thing, just the S optional as well.
只要我一次又一次地应用同样的原则
So long as I'm applying the same principles again and again,
无论是小规模的还是大规模的
either on a small scale or a bigger scale,
将其中一个嵌套在另一个中是完全没有问题的
it's totally fine to nest one of these inside of the other.
现在对这些改进中的任何一个提出问题
Questions now on any of these refinements
对于这个解析 这个对推特的分析？
to this parsing, this analyzing of Twitter?
观众：如果我们在这个WWW点旁边加一个竖线 会怎么样？
AUDIENCE: What if we put a vertical bar besides this www dot?
大卫·马兰：如果我们在那里用竖条呢？
DAVID MALAN: What if we use a vertical bar there?
所以我们也可以做类似的事情
So we could do something like that, too.
我们可以做这样的事情
We could do something like this.
我可以用www.来代替问号 或者什么都不做
Instead of the question mark, I could do www dot or nothing
只留下那个和圆括号
and just leave that and the parentheses.
这也很好
That, too, would be fine.
我个人倾向于不喜欢它 因为它稍微少了一点
I personally tend not to like that, because it's a little less
对我来说很明显--等一下
obvious to me-- wait, a minute.
这是故意的吗 还是我忘了把我的想法
Is that deliberate, or did I forget to finish my thought by putting something
在垂直横杆之后？
after the vertical bar?
但这也是允许的 如果你是这个意思的话
But that, too, would be allowed there as well, if that's what you mean.
关于我们把东西放在哪里的其他问题
Other questions on where we left things here,
我们把协议也设为可选的吗？
where we made the protocol optional, too?
观众：如果我们有括号 会怎么样？
AUDIENCE: What happens if we have parenthesis,
在里面我们有另一个括号 还有另一个括号？
and inside we have another parenthesis, and another parenthesis?
会不会互相干扰？
Will it interfere with each other?
大卫·马兰：如果你把括号放在括号里
DAVID MALAN: If you have parentheses inside of parentheses, that,
太好了 完全没问题
too, is totally fine.
事实上 这应该是今天令人放心的教训之一
And indeed, that should be one of the reassuring lessons today.
诚然 这些正则表达式中的每一个都很复杂
As complicated as each of these regular expressions has admittedly gotten,
我只是应用了完全相同的原则和语法
I'm just applying the exact same principles and the exact same syntax
再三
again and again.
所以把括号放在括号里是完全可以的
So it's totally fine to have parentheses inside of parentheses
如果他们各自解决不同的问题
if they're each solving different problems.
事实上 我今天最强调的一课
And in fact, the lesson I would really emphasize the most today
如果你试着写出来你不会高兴的
is that you will not be happy if you try to write out
一次完成整个复杂的正则表达式
a whole complicated regular expression all at once.
如果你像我一样 你会失败的
Like, if you're anything like me, you will fail,
你将很难找到这个错误
and you will have trouble finding the mistake.
因为我的天 看看这些东西
Because my god, look at these things.
即使在这么多年后的我看来 它们也是神秘的
They are, even to me all these years later, cryptic.
我认为 更好的方法是 无论你是编程新手
The better way, I would argue, whether you're new to programming
或者像我这样老了 就是带着这些孩子
or is old to it as I am, is to just take these baby
步骤 这些渐进的步骤 你可以做一些简单的事情
steps, these incremental steps where you do something simple,
你要确保它起作用
you make sure it works.
你再增加一项功能 确保它能正常工作
You add one more feature, make sure it works.
再添加一项功能 确保其正常工作
Add one more feature, make sure it works.
希望到最后 因为你已经完成了其中的每一步
And hopefully, by the end, because you've done each of those steps one
在某个时候 整件事对你来说都会有意义的
at a time, the whole thing will make sense to you.
但你也会在每一次转弯时都正确地完成每一步
But you'll also have gotten each of those steps correct at each turn.
所以 请务必避免尝试的倾向
So please, do avoid the inclination to try
想出又长又复杂的正则表达式
to come up with long, sophisticated regular expressions
一下子 因为这不是很好地利用时间
all at once, because it's just not a good use of a time
如果你盯着它 试图找到你认为的错误
if you then stare at it trying to find a mistake that you
如果你做的事情更循序渐进 你可能会发现
could have caught if you did things more incrementally instead.
好的
All right.
可以说 仍然存在至少一个问题
There still remains, arguably, at least one problem
有了这个解决方案 即使我是
with this solution in that even though I'm
调用re.Sub以不使用任何内容替换URL
calling re.sub to substitute the URL with nothing,
引用 不引用 然后在我的最后一行代码中 第6行
quote, unquote, I then in my final line of code, line 6,
我只是盲目地假设这一切都奏效了
am just blindly assuming that it all worked,
接下来 我将打印出用户名
and I'm going to go ahead and print out the username.
但如果用户--
But what if the user--
如果我在这里清空屏幕并运行twitter.py的python--
if I clear my screen here and run python of twitter.py--
甚至连Twitter URL都不输入？
doesn't even type a Twitter URL?
如果他们做了像https://google.com/ 这样的事情怎么办
What if they do something like https://google.com/,
就像完全无关 不管是什么原因
like completely unrelated, for whatever reason,
输入 这不是他们的Twitter用户名
Enter, that is not their Twitter username.
所以我们需要一些条件逻辑 我认为
So we need to have some conditional logic, I would argue,
所以为了这个程序 我们只打印出
so that for this program's sake, we're only printing out
或者 在后端系统中 我们只保存到数据库或CSV中
or, in a back end system, we're only saving into our database or a CSV
如果我们确实匹配了正确的模式 请将用户名归档
file the username if we actually matched the proper pattern.
因此 与其使用对清理数据有用的re.sub.
So rather than use re.sub, which is useful for cleaning up data,
就像我们在这里做的那样 处理掉我们不想要的东西
as we've done here to get rid of something we don't want there,
为什么我们不回到我们今天开始的地方去重新搜索
why don't we go back to re.search, where we began today,
并用它来解决同样的问题 但以一种有条件的方式
and use it to solve this same problem but in a way that's conditional,
因此我可以自信地说 是或不是 在我的节目结束时
whereby I can confidently say, yes or no, at the end of my program,
这里是用户名 还是这里不是？
here's the username, or here it is not?
所以现在让我继续下去
So let me go ahead now.
我会在这里清理我的终端窗口
And I'll clear my terminal window here.
我要保留大部分--
I'm going to keep most of--
我将保持前两行 与我导入Re的位置相同
I'm going to keep the first two lines the, same where I import re,
然后我从用户那里获得URL
and I get the URL from the user.
但这一次 让我们开始吧
But this time, let's do this.
这一次让我们搜索 使用re.earch而不是re.sub.
Let's this time search for, using re.search instead of re.sub,
以下是
the following.
我将从字符串的开头开始匹配
I'm going to start matching at the beginning of the string, https,
问号使S成为可选的 冒号 斜杠 斜杠
question mark to make the S optional, colon, slash, slash,
我将把我的www设置为可选 在那里打上问号
I'm going to make my www optional by putting that in question marks there,
然后是一个带有文字圆点的twitter.com 这样我就可以在这个问题上保持领先
then a twitter.com with a literal dot there so I stay ahead of that issue,
也是 然后是一条斜线
too, then a slash.
然后 这就是Davidjmaran应该去的地方
And then well, this is where davidjmalan is supposed to go.
我如何检测到这一点？
How do I detect this?
好吧 我想我可以容忍URL末尾的任何内容
Well, I think I'll just tolerate anything at the end of the URL here.
好的 最后的$符号 结束引号
All right, $ sign at the very end, close quote.
目前 我要规定我们不能
For the moment, I'm going to stipulate that we're not
我会担心结尾处的问号或散列
going to worry about question marks at the end or hashes,
就像URL中的片段ID一样
like for fragment IDs in URLs.
为了简单起见 我们现在假设URL只是
We're going to assume for simplicity now that the URL just
仅以用户名结尾
ends with the username alone.
现在我该怎么办呢？
Now what am I going to do?
嗯 我想特别搜索这个URL
Well, I want to search for this URL specifically,
我要忽略凯斯 所以请再说一遍
and I'm going to ignore case, so re.IGNORECASE,
应用从以前学到的同样的教训
applying that same lesson learned from before.
Re.search、recall将向您返回您捕获的匹配项
re.search, recall, will return to you the matches you've captured.
那么 我想捕捉什么呢？
Well, what do I want to capture?
好的 我想在这里捕获twitter.com URL右侧的所有内容
Well, I want to capture everything to the right of the twitter.com URL here.
因此 让我用括号将应该是用户用户名的内容括起来
So let me surround what should be the user's username with parentheses,
不是为了让它们成为可选的 而是说 “捕捉这组字符 ”
not for making them optional but to say, "capture this set of characters."
现在 re.earch recall 返回一个答案
Now, re.search, recall, returns an answer.
Matches将再次成为我的变量名 但我可以随心所欲地命名它
matches will be my variable name again, but I could call it anything I want.
然后我就能做到这一点
And then I can do this.
如果匹配 现在我知道我能做到
If matches, now I know I can do this.
让我们打印出格式字符串用户名冒号
Let's print out the format string, username colon.
然后我想打印出什么呢？
And then what do I want to print out?
嗯 我想我想把比赛打印出来 第一组是我的比赛
Well, I think I want to print out matches.group 1 for my matched
用户名
username.
好的
All right.
那么 我在做什么 只是为了回顾一下？
So what am I doing just to recap?
第1行 我正在导入库
Line 1, I'm importing the library.
第2行 我从用户那里获取URL
Line 2, I'm getting the URL from the user.
因此 这并不是什么新鲜事
So nothing new there.
第5行 我正在搜索用户的URL 如这里的第二个参数所示
Line 5, I'm searching the user's URL, as indicated here as the second argument,
对于此正则表达式 此模式
for this regular expression, this pattern.
我用圆括号将圆点+括起来
I have surrounded the dot + with parentheses
所以他们最终会被捕获 所以我可以提取
so that they are captured ultimately, so I can extract,
在最后一个场景中 是指用户的用户名
in this final scenario, the user's username.
如果我真的找到了匹配项 而匹配项不是零
If I indeed got a match, and matches is non-none,
它实际上包含一些匹配项 然后且仅在那时 打印出用户名
it is actually containing some match, then and only then, print out username.
这样的话 现在让我试试这个
In this way, let me try this now.
如果我运行twitter.py的PYTHON并输入https://www.google.com/
If I run python of twitter.py and type in https://www.google.com/,
现在什么都不打印了
now nothing gets printed.
所以我至少解决了我们刚才看到的错误
So I've at least solved the mistake we just saw,
我只是假设我的代码起作用了
where I was just assuming that my code worked.
现在 我正在确保我已经搜索并找到了Twitter URL前缀
Now I'm making sure that I have searched for and found the Twitter URL prefix.
好的
All right.
好了 现在让我们来真的来吧
Well, let's run this for real now.
Twitter.py https://twitter.com/davidjmalan.的巨蟒
Python of twitter.py https://twitter.com/davidjmalan.
但请注意 我可以使用HTTP 我可以使用WWW
But note, I could use HTTP, I could use www.
我只需要在这里继续 然后按Enter键
I'm just going to go ahead here and hit Enter.
呃 没有
Huh, none.
到底出了什么问题？
What has gone wrong?
这个更微妙一些
This one's a bit more subtle.
但是为什么Matchs.Group 1什么都不包含呢？
But why does matches.group 1 contain nothing?
等一下
Wait a minute.
让我--也许我做错了
Let me-- maybe I did this wrong.
也许--也许我们需要万维网？
Maybe-- maybe do we need the www?
让我再运行一次
Let me run it again.
我们开始吧https：// 让我们添加一个www.twitter.com/davidjmalan
So here we go. https://, let's add a www.twitter.com/davidjmalan.
好吧
All right.
输入.
Enter.
吼 吼 吼
Ho, ho, ho.
怎么回事？
What is going on?
观众：你必须说第二组
AUDIENCE: You have to say group 2.
大卫·马兰：我不得不说第二组？
DAVID MALAN: I have to say group 2?
好吧 等等--哦 对了 因为我们的子域是可选的
Well, wait-- oh, right, because we had the subdomain was optional.
为了使它成为可选的 我需要在这里使用括号
And to make it optional, I needed to use parentheses here.
所以我说零或上
And so I then said zero or on.
好的.
OK.
所以这意味着实际上 我是无意的 但通过设计
So that means that actually, I'm unintentionally but by design
捕获www点 或者如果它之前不存在
capturing the www dot, or none of it if it wasn't there before,
但我这里还有第二个匹配因为我
but I have a second match over here because I
还有第二个括号
have a second set of parentheses.
所以我想 是的 让我改变matches.group 1
So I think, yep, let me change matches.group 1
到matches.group 2 让我们运行这个
to matches.group 2, and let's run this.
Python of twitter.py https://www.twitter--
让我们这样做 twitter.com/davidjmalan 输入
let's do this, twitter.com/davidjmalan, Enter,
现在我们拿到了用户名
and now we've got access to the username.
让我再把它收紧一点
Let me go ahead and tighten it up a little bit further.
如果你喜欢我们的新朋友
If you like our new friend--
很难不喜欢
it's hard not to like.
如果我们喜欢我们的老朋友海象操作员 让我们继续
If we like our old friend the walrus operator, let's go ahead
再加上这个让事情更紧密
and add this just to tighten things up.
让我们回到VS代码 让我们去掉不必要的条件
Let me go back to VS Code here, and let me get rid of the unnecessary condition
然后在这里合并 如果匹配等于这个的话
there and combine it up here, if matches equals that.
但是让我们将单个赋值运算符改为海象运算符
But let's change the single assignment operator to the walrus operator.
现在我把事情弄得更紧了
Now I've tightened things up further.
但我敢打赌 这里可能有另一个解决方案
But I bet, I bet, I bet there might be another solution here.
事实上 我们可以回到这最后一组语法
And indeed, it turns out that we can come back to this final set of syntax.
回想一下 当我们引入这些括号时
Recall that when we introduce these parentheses,
我们这样做是为了我们可以做A或B 比如 用竖条
we did it so that we could do A or B, for instance, with the vertical bar.
然后你甚至可以组合不止一个酒吧
Then you can even combine more than just one bar.
我们使用组来组合想法 如 www.
We use the group to combine ideas like the, www dot.
然后在底部这里有一个公认的奇怪语法 直到现在
And then there's this admittedly weird syntax at the bottom here, up until now
未使用
not used.
有一个非捕获版本的圆括号
There is a non-capturing version of parentheses
如果你想逻辑地使用圆括号
if you want to use parentheses logically because you need to,
但你不想费心去捕捉结果
but you don't want to bother capturing the result.
这可能是一个更好的解决方案
And this would arguably be a better solution
因为 是的 如果我回到VS Code
here, because, yes, if I go back to VS Code, I do
至少需要用括号将www点括起来
need to surround the www dot with parentheses, at least
就像我在这里写正则表达式一样 因为我想
as I've written my regex here, because I wanted
在后面加上问号
to put the question mark after it.
但我不需要那个www点回来
But I don't need the www dot coming back.
实际上 我们只提取我们关心的数据
In fact, let's only extract the data we care about,
这样我以后就不会有困惑了
just so there's no confusion down the road, for me,
或者我的同事 或者我的老师
or my colleagues, or my teachers.
我能怎么办？
So what could I do?
这张幻灯片的语法是使用问号和冒号
Well, the syntax per this slide is to use a question mark and a colon
紧接着左括号
immediately after the open parentheses.
不可否认 它看起来很奇怪
It looks weird admittedly.
如果你们有编程经验
Those of you who have prior programming experience
我可能会从三元运算符中识别语法 执行if else all in one
might recognize the syntax from ternary operators, doing an if else all in one
线
line.
在插入语的开头加上一个问号冒号
A question mark colon at the beginning of that parenthetical
意思是 我用括号把这些东西组合在一起
means, yes, I'm using parentheses to group these things together,
但不 你不需要去捕捉它们
but no, you do not need to capture them instead.
所以我现在可以把代码改回matches.group 1.
So I can change my code back now to matches.group 1.
我会在这里清空屏幕 运行twitter.py的python
I'll clear my screen here, run python of twitter.py.
我将再次运行https://twitter.com/davidjmalan
I'll again run here https://twitter.com/davidjmalan
不管有没有www
with or without the www.
现在 我真的找回了那个用户名
And now, I indeed get back that username.
对这些最后的技巧有什么问题吗？
Any questions, then, on these final techniques?
观众：首先 我们能不能把
AUDIENCE: So first of all, could we move the ^ right
在Twitter的开头 然后从那里开始阅读
at the beginning of Twitter, and then just start reading from there,
然后在此之前摆脱所有其他的东西
and then get rid of everything else before that, the kind of www issues
我们拥有的
that we had?
然后我的第二个问题是 我想
And then my second question is, how would we use kind of, I guess,
一个列表或者一个字典来对.com之类的东西进行排序
either a list or a dictionary to sort the .com kind of thing,
因为我们有. co.uk 和类似的东西
because we have .co.uk, and that kind of stuff.
我们如何将其带入re函数？
How would we bring that into the re function?
大卫·马兰：一个很好的问题 但不是
DAVID MALAN: A good question but no.
如果我把^移到twitter.com之前 并扔掉协议和www
If I move the ^ before twitter.com and throw away the protocol and the www,
那么用户将不得不按字面意思键入twitter.com/username
then the user is going to have to type in literally twitter.com/username.
他们甚至不能输入其他东西
They can't even type in that other stuff.
因此 这将是一种倒退 是一种倒退
So that would be a regression, a step back.
至于.com、.org和.edu等等
As for the .com, the .org, and .edu, and so forth,
简短的答案是 这里有许多不同的解决方案
the short answer is there's many different solutions here.
如果我想严格对待.com--假设Twitter可能拥有
If I wanted to be stringent about .com-- and suppose that Twitter probably owns
多个域名 尽管他们倾向于只使用这个域名
multiple domain names, even though they tend to use just this one.
假设他们也有像.org这样的网站
Suppose they have something like .org as well.
您可以在这里使用更多的括号 并执行类似这样的操作--com或org
You could use more parentheses here and do something like this-- com or org.
我可能想进去加一个问号
I'd probably want to go in and add a question mark
冒号将其设置为非捕获 因为我不在乎
colon to make it non-capturing, because I don't care which
是的 我只想容忍这两种情况
it is, I just want to tolerate both.
或者 我们可以抓住这一点
Alternatively, we could capture that.
我们可以做这样的事情 我们做点+ 所以
We could do something like this, where we do dot + so as
才能真正捕捉到这一点
to actually capture that.
然后我们可以做这样的事情
And then we could do something like this.
如果matches.group 1现在等于com 那么我们可以支持这一点
If matches.group 1 now equals equals com, then we could support this.
因此 您可以想象仅通过提取顶层
So you could imagine factoring out the logic just by extracting the Top-Level
域 或TLD 然后只需使用Python代码 也许是列表 也许
Domain, or TLD, and then just using Python code, maybe a list, maybe
一本词典 在正则表达式之外的其他地方进行验证
a dictionary, to validate elsewhere, outside of the regex,
如果这真的是你所期待的
if it's, in fact, what you expect.
不过 就目前而言 我们让事情变得简单
For now, though, we kept things simple.
在这种情况下 我们只关注.com
We focused only on the .com in this case.
让我们对这个程序做最后一次更改
Let's make one final change to this program
所以我们的定义更具体一点
so that we're being a little more specific with the definition
推特用户名的
of a Twitter username.
事实证明 我们在这里有点太慷慨了 因此我们
It turns out that we're being a little too generous over here, whereby we're
接受一个或多个任何字符
accepting one or more of any character.
我查看了Twitter的文档
I checked the documentation for Twitter.
推特只支持字母表中的字母a到Z
And Twitter only supports letters of the alphabet, a through Z,
数字0到9 或下划线 所以不只是点
numbers 0 through 9, or underscores, so not just dot,
从字面上看 它是任何东西
which is literally anything.
所以让我继续下去 在这里更准确地说
So let me go ahead and be more precise here.
在我最后 让我继续说
At the end of my string, let me go ahead and say,
方括号中的这组符号
this set of symbols in square brackets.
接下来我会说a到Z 0到9 还有一个下划线
I'm going to go ahead and say a through Z, 0 through 9, and an underscore.
因为 再说一次 这些是唯一有效的符号
Because, again, those are the only valid symbols.
我不需要麻烦大写的A或小写的z
I don't need to bother with an uppercase A or a lowercase z,
因为我们这里用的是RE.IGNORECASE
because we're using re.IGNORECASE over here.
但我想确保我现在不仅能容忍一个或多个
But I want to make sure now that I tolerate not only one or more
这些符号在这里 但也可能是URL末尾的一些其他东西
of these symbols here but also maybe some other stuff at the end of the URL.
我现在不介意有一个斜杠或一个问号
I'm now going to be OK with there being a slash, or a question mark,
或URL结尾处的散列 所有这些都是URL中的有效符号
or a hash at the end of the URL, all of which are valid symbols in a URL,
但我从推特的文件中得知
but I know from the Twitter's documentation,
不是用户名的一部分
are not part of the username.
好的
All right.
现在 我将继续运行twitter.py one的蟒蛇
Now I'm going to go ahead and run python of twitter.py one
最后一次 也许输入https://twitter.com/davidjmalan
final time, typing in https://twitter.com/davidjmalan, maybe
有 也许没有尾部的斜杠
with, maybe without a trailing slash.
但希望 在我最大的手指交叉在这里 我现在要继续
But hopefully, with my biggest fingers crossed here, I'm going to go ahead now
然后按回车键 谢天谢地 我的用户名确实是davidjmaran
and hit Enter, and thankfully my username is, indeed, davidjmalan.
那么 在正则表达式的世界里还有什么呢
So what more is there in the world of regular expressions
那这个自己的图书馆呢？
and this own library?
不只是re.earch和re.sub. 还有其他功能
Not just re.search and also re.sub, there's other functions, too.
有re.plit 你可以通过它来拆分字符串 而不是
There's re.split, via which you can split a string, not
使用一个或多个特定字符 如逗号和空格
using a specific character or characters like a comma and a space,
但也有多个角色
but multiple characters as well.
甚至还有像re.findall这样的功能
And there's even functions like re.findall,
它可以让您搜索同一图案的多个副本
which can allow you to search for multiple copies of the same pattern
在字符串中的不同位置 这样您可能可以
in different places in a string so that you can perhaps
操控不止一个人
manipulate more than just one.
所以在一天结束的时候 你真的学会了一门完全不同的语言
So at the end of the day now, you've really learned a whole other language,
就像正则表达式一样 我们已经在Python中使用了它们
like that of regular expressions, and we've used them in Python.
但这些正则表达式实际上也存在于许多语言中
But these regular expressions actually exist in so many languages, too,
其中包括Java、Java和Ruby等等
among them JavaScript, and Java, and Ruby, and more.
所以有了这种新的语言 尽管它确实是神秘的
So with this new language, even though it's admittedly cryptic
当你第一次使用它时 你就拥有了这种新发现的能力
when you use it for the first time, you have this newfound ability
为了表达这些模式 同样 您可以使用它们来验证数据
to express these patterns that, again, you can use to validate data,
清理数据 甚至从任何数据集中提取数据
to clean up data, or even extract data, and from any data set
你可能已经想好了
you might have in mind.
本周就到这里吧
That's it for this week.
我们下次再见
We will see you next time.